{"_id": "c725b7f7", "question": "Is the 500 yard free style a choice stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8c336dd6", "question": "If there is no other choice, can I use motor/engine oil as replacement for 2T (two-stroke) oil?", "answers": "You might want to look into the flash point specification of 2T oil, and I’m willing to bet it’d be quite a bit lower than conventional motor oil which is formulated to have a high flash point typically in the 450 F range.\nIf the 2T oil flash point is lower, then it suggests using conventional motor oil will leave gummy deposits from an inefficient burn in the combustion chamber.\nBut in a pinch, if you must, like running a generator in an emergency, then I imagine it won’t do much harm and it’d be a worthwhile trade-off."}
{"_id": "e4890bd6", "question": "How do I explain my academic choices that resulted in failing 3 semesters in a row after a small stroke? I’ve been enrolled in a community college 5 years later and doing very well. After the stroke, I thought I was “okay”.", "answers": "I’m going to operate under the assumption that your doctor told you that you could return to life as usual as soon as you were feeling up to it. A couple of other assumptions may also have accidentally been made for the sake of the narrative.\nThat said, you had a stroke. You underestimated the effects it would have on you after the fact, so you went back to school before you were actually ready. That didn’t go so well, because you weren’t actually as well off as you thought you were. Once you gave yourself time to fully recover, the healthy, rational decision making version of you, recognized it, and then went back to school to work back up to where you had been. Now you’re ready to challenge yourself, and you’ve proven that you’re up to the task now that you’re recovered.\nThat’s the way I would frame it. Best of luck to you in all future endeavors."}
{"_id": "fe882f4a", "question": "Is the well-being of older adults the result of their individual lifestyle choices and financial planning? How much are events such as heart attack and stroke a result of lifestyle choices?", "answers": "I see it the other way. One’s lifestyle choices can be derailed by a disease or accident that leaves one unable to earn a living.\nThere are certainly people who have brought on their own diabetes or heart disease, and have never made an effort to prevent it. There are others who have done everything right, but lost the genetic lottery.\nMost people do make some effort to plan for the future of their health and finances. Some folks end up old, healthy and solvent without trying all that hard. Others who actually tried harder may have bad luck that wipes them out.\nIt’s always possible to twist history to prove that someone didn’t do everything- every single possible thing- to prevent problems. Basically, we are human, and we want to do what we want to do. Or maybe our family, schools and community didn’t help us to develop excellent habits.\nI think we should balance judgment with compassion when dealing with our human friends and neighbors."}
{"_id": "4119411b", "question": "What was your worst stroke of bad luck that made you reconsider recent life choices?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0b2d7f7d", "question": "Would a mongoose excursion mountain bike be a good choice for mounting a 2-stroke engine?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "71a2ad1b", "question": "My mom had a mild cerebral stroke 2 months back, she has recovered a lot and I want to get a follow-up checkup done. Should I be going to a neurologist or an internal medicine specialist would be a better choice?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d772f73e", "question": "My mother's obese. She is a recovering stroke patient and has coronary heart disease. How can I know if she's taken in just enough food in her diet?", "answers": "Is your mother a willing participant in her new dietary regime? Problems may arise if she is not. Always important to get the patient's co-operation. Get her to stop smoking and moderate her alcohol intake too, if necessary.\nAn assessment by a professional dietician of her normal intake is the place to start. Is your mother able and willing to keep an ACCURATE dietary record for a week or two? That would be quite important.\nWhen the dietician has made recommendations you could supervise the purchase of the necessary items and remove all illegal/immoral/fattening items from your mother's house, thus removing temptation.\nKeeping an eye on her weight at, perhaps, weekly intervals - same time/same day each week - and charting the result may help.\nSome elderly people muddle along on jam sandwiches and tea. This is clearly a grossly deficient diet and will lead to important deficiencies of vitamins and minerals. Your dietician may recommend an all-in-one vitamin supplement.\nGraded exercise is an important part of your mother's new lifestyle. See if there are any suitable classes/groups locally that she could attend for guidance and encouragement. The social aspect of such groups is often beneficial too. On line and DVD programs can help too. Simply walking round the house or down to the end of the street and back several times each day is a start.\nWholesome pre-prepared meals are available to keep in the freezer. They are for microwaving usually but can be ovened too. Diet size portions are usually available. A supply of suitable snacks will help prevent your mother from nibbling unhelpfully between meals - fresh fruit is the obvious starting place.\nAbove all, positive and optimistic encouragement is needed."}
{"_id": "2414d672", "question": "What are the best exercises for a recovering stroke patient with left side weakness?", "answers": "There is no such thing as best exercise. Stroke patient needs multidisciplinary rehabilitation treatment, including physical therapy, occupational therapy, nurse, doctor, social worker, speech therapist, psychology. It’s impossible to do it with no guidance and even then - most patients remain with some disability afterwards"}
{"_id": "e34df8de", "question": "As an occupational therapist, in your experience do recovering stroke patients relearning handwriting need bigger ruled paper like young children, or do they tend to prefer or need standard smaller-ruled writing paper?", "answers": "Thank-you for writing a good question I don’t mind answering.\nAs my own rule, I don’t use lined paper for my stroke patients when re-learning a fine motor task such as handwriting.\nRuled or lined paper forces the sense of “perfection” early on. Firsly, the patient needs to feel some success with the task. Just holding the writing implement and making a mark—any mark—on the page is success.\nI usually have my patients who are working on handwriting first re-learn a good grip on the pen/ pencil/marker. This may take some time and adaptation. Next, I have them work on vertical lines followed by diagonal lines, then horizontal lines, then circles. With these tools, they can then begin forming letters, usually copying or tracing first, especially the patients who have some aphasia or apraxia.\nThis is a short answer, but generally this is how I like to work on fine motor tasks. Break then down to the components and work on each of those first."}
{"_id": "1b653789", "question": "Do people fully recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Speaking as someone who has had one, I can say that is possible, although the extent of the stroke is probably unique to the individual and largely depends on what areas of the brain are affected and how the brain is able to ‘reroute’ past the damaged areas.\nWith loss of motor control, some alleviation may be possible by moving limbs in a recognised way, mimicking walking for example or raising one’s arm, which might help to stimulate the growth of new connections but this is not always very successful.\nIn my case, aphasia was the main symptom, the inability to speak, write or to regain even a partial command of my native language. However, a daily regimen of vocal exercises in front of a mirror (I always wondered what my neighbours thought of me reading aloud from ‘Winnie the Pooh’ or ‘House at Pooh Corner’ during such exercises) and the constant reference to a good thesaurus meant that I was back up to speed within, I guess, two years.\nI am still dyslexic when I write (but my typing appears to be OK) and have not tried to access my foreign language abilities very much, although I can follow a performed ‘Les Fourberies de Scapin’ in the original providing that I have the text of the play in front of me.\nHowever, the most important thing, in my view, is the support of one’s family and friends, the people who knew you from before the stroke and can offer feedback on how well you seem to them at all points in the recovery process; are you genuinely improving or is it just wishful thinking?"}
{"_id": "4abd3bd1", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Hi\nI am stroke survivor (Feb 2012) . It is now 5 years and to think it was FIVE long years or\n2628000 seconds or 43800 minutes or 1825 days ,. It is only the mind that matters ,.\nI have the memory of going to the Hospital on the the 7th ,30th,45th day and after that it became every 2 months,. I was BACK the day when I was back at Home.\nThe subject of this note should how QUICK does it take for an average person to get over a stroke ,.It is in micro seconds ….Mind i was a smoker ,used to eat every thing ,.\nGanesh"}
{"_id": "c98d0d03", "question": "What's the best course of action when recovering from strokes?", "answers": "Immediate treatment is the Number One course for successful stroke recovery. The source of the injury must be identified (is it a clot or a bleed?) and the appropriate treatment to abate that event applied. Since most strokes seem to be ischemic (clot) at first glance, anti-clotting medications can \"bust\" the clot and restore blood flow to the affected areas of the brain. If this treatment is accomplished within a few hours (used to be a three hour window, but that window's been opened a bit wider: Time window for\nstroke\ntreatment should be extended\n) damage cane be limited and usually treatable.\nThe second most-important factor in stroke treatment is swift, aggressive and global therapies, physical, occupational and speech. Physical therapy addresses the need to \"re-teach\" muscles how to work, and to provide the opportunity for damaged neurons to re-route signals around damaged areas. Occupational therapy does this, also, but in the teaching of strategies to accomplish every day tasks, occupational therapy has a terrific track record in that \"re-teaching\". Speech therapy is not limited to speech, itself, but to cognition, also, in addition to swallowing issues. All of the therapies and techniques used help the brain recover from the insult of stroke.\nIn the event of a suspected stroke:\nGet the victim to a hospital ASAP\nThe hospital administers the correct treatments to bust the clot or stop the bleed ASAP.\nTherapies start early and continue until there is no further progress, at which time strategies are worked out to accomplish tasks in weakened areas.\nSometimes, some areas of the brain are so damaged they cannot \"come back\", and the victim needs assistance for the rest of their lives. But advances in treating stroke have become routine in Western medicine, and the outcomes have improved by a very large measure. What would have killed a victim even 25 years ago, is nearly completely recoverable now, as long as swift medical and therapeutic intervention is provided."}
{"_id": "dd2958e8", "question": "Is there a way for a person to fully recover from a stroke?", "answers": "It's going to be according to what was damaged in the brain- what areas and how badly- how soon and how much therapy a person receives, and how able they are to utilize the therapy they receive.\nA stroke can cause massive damage to the brains, killing whole swathes of brain tissue and, generally, neurons don't grow back. ( Page on jneurosci.org\n) So, if the clot or bleed which caused the CVA (cerebral vascular accident) was big, full recovery may be impossible.\nIf both drug and physical/occupational/speech therapies are started immediately, stroke victims can recover a surprising amount of functioning; surprising for the state in which they were brought in to the Emergency Room, anyway. Clot-busting drugs along with blood thinners help to clear away lingering debris in the brain's circulatory system and also keep a good, steady flow of blood, oxygen and nutrients in to the damaged area. That helps tremendously.\nThe therapies mentioned above, though, are less efficacious if the damage is severe. PT, which usually focuses on physical strengthening of an affected body part and overall conditioning, and OT, which focuses on every day tasks and abilities, don't do a person who is completely right-side paralyzed much good until the brain heals a bit from the insult of the stroke. There are improvements, certainly, but until the brain starts re-routing itself around damaged areas, these therapies are mostly a holding pattern. Same with speech therapy, although it is speech, with its emphasis on cognition, which can get the ball really rolling. Real improvement starts to be seen about week 3 post CVA, with continued improvement for about 18 months. After that, a plateau is usually reached, and few people can afford to continue the intensive therapy needed to see further improvement.\nTwo and three years later, there can be little improvement in functional abilities, although strength in musculature can help minimize deficits.\nI'm sorry your friend has had to go through this, and will continue with this disability for the rest of her life. The best thing you can do now is to treat her as a friend, help her when she requests it, and not allow her deficits to cause you to see her as someone to be pitied. No one gains from pity."}
{"_id": "d3a0e18f", "question": "Why can one never recover from a stroke?", "answers": "There are two types of strokes that can occur within the hunan body.\nThe first type is ischaemic stroke which is related to the issue to deficiency of oxygen within the blood going to the brain, or blood in general. This could be the result of a blood clotting somewhere or the narrowing of blood vessels. Various factors can affect both of these to accelerate (in the case of narrowing of blood vessels) and more likely of blood clotting as well. These include:\n1) Smoking (Narrowing of the veins)\n2) Drinking (Related to Obesity)\n3) Drugs (NSAIDs aka Non-Steroidal Anti-Inflammatory Drugs) Not all but some of them double the risk of blood clotting.\n4) foreign objects in the blood which can cause embolism\n5) Obesity\n6) Cancer\n7) Heart Disease\n8) High HDL cholesterol levels\n9) Ageing\nAs well as other factors. These factors are not in isolation but make a greatly significant risk when compounded together.\nAnother cause can be atrial fibrillation which is a blood clot that happens near the heart and can break off and cause a bigger issue near blood vessels going to the brain.\nThe other type of stroke is called haemorrhagic stroke (also known as cerebral and intracranial haemorrhages) which is when a blood vessel within the brain bursts open and releases blood into and around the brain\nThe main cause of this would be high blood pressure which can weaken the arteries within the brain. The arteries eventually come to a point where it can not contain that pressure and so burst open.\n\"Things that increase the risk of high blood pressure include:\nbeing overweight or obese\ndrinking excessive amounts of alcohol\nsmoking\na lack of exercise\nstress, which may cause a temporary rise in blood pressure\" - http://www.nhs.uk/Conditions/Stroke/Pages/Whosatriskpage.aspx\nAlthough this type of stroke is less common, it causes a lot more damage to the brain.\nAnother cause of rupture is the result of a balloon-like expansion of the blood vessels (a brain aneurysm) or from the blood vessel within the brain being badly formed.\n\nDepending on the severity of the damage caused to the brain, the neurons that died will not grow back. However if the severity of the damage was significantly low, new connections between neurons can be made to provide some functionality back. (This is why you hear about patients that could move their fingers or show some other movement through therapy and rehabilitation)."}
{"_id": "6113fe34", "question": "Can someone recover completely from a stroke? If yes, how long does it take for a person to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "That is an impossible question to answer. Each stroke is different and in a room full of 100 stroke victims, no two strokes will have been the same. How much of the brain died? Where exactly did the brain cells die? Strokes aren’t a hit and it’s over. A stroke continues for 24–48 hours with more brain cells dying every minute.\nI had a major ischemic stroke. My right side was totally paralyzed head to foot and my speech was gone. Despite the years of therapy, I have not had a complete recovery. I recovered my speech after some time and with speech therapy, it’s not the same as before. But! I’m so glad I have it! I had occupational and physical therapy in the hospital for six weeks then at home 6 days/week for most of the year. Therapy is ongoing, for me, for the rest of my life. So recoveries are all different too. But therapy is forever. Or you can lose some of your past gains.\nSo the question asks about a complete recovery but with no details of the initial damage and losses or the kind of therapy and whether it was begun immediately. No one can give you the kind of answer you are looking for. Hasn’t the doctor discussed the prognosis with you? He alone would have the information needed for that assessment.\nI wish you or the patient the best of luck!"}
{"_id": "b636e8db", "question": "Can a person be fully recovered after brain stroke?", "answers": "Yes, a person can be fully recovered after brain stroke but it will depend on condition to condition. If there is a very little portion of Brain is damaged due to stroke then the recovery is possible within few weeks but if it damaged a major portion of the brain then there are chances that full recovery may not possible.\nIf you want treatment for Brain Stroke then you can consult with Dr. Vikram Bohra who working as a Neurologist in Jaipur\n."}
{"_id": "33751d05", "question": "What did you do to help yourself recover from your stroke?", "answers": "My stroke happened in April of 2011. I was a freshman in college at the time, before the stroke, I was a very active student. I was in cross country and other sports in high school, so I never thought that I could have a stroke… at least not at that age.\nMy stroke was a hemorrhagic stroke which happened due to an arteriovenous malformation (AVM). When it ruptured, I went into a comma. While at the hospital, I had a respiratory failure, and the doctors said that I only had 10 percent chance of surviving. I survived. I did not really have any deficits after the Stroke. Like I mentioned before, I was a freshman in college, and because of the stroke, I had to drop off school.\nAfter the stroke, all I wanted to do was to go back to school. In order to have my medical hold cleared, I had to undergo speech therapy. I could speak and have conversations, but the neurologists said that because of the location of rupture, the area of the brain that deals with planning and higher level thinking was affected. I did not feel any different from before. At least I did not notice a difference.\nI was able to go back to school the following semester. I had constant medical visits to determine the best treatment for the AVM. At that time, my health was my main priority, school was not on the top of my list and I failed some classes. Now that I think about it, I should have listened to the therapist who told me to take a break. She said that my brain was not the same, but I was (or am) stubborn and did not listen.\nAfter several MRIs and Angiograms, I underwent a radiation treatment. I was still going to school. I would go to the radiation treatment once a week for two hours for about three months, and then I would go to class. That semester, I also failed several classes. My GPA went below the requirements for my scholarships, but I was done with the treatment. My scholarship was “for four years, or until you gradate, whichever comes first”, so I could not afford to fall behind.\nAfter that semester, I registered for summer classes in order to catch up with my graduation schedule. I took summer courses every summer until my senior year, and took 18 hours every semester. I was able to raise my GPA, and I graduated within four years.\nSo to answer your question: what really helped me recover from my stroke was being busy. I did not let the stroke change who I was or change the goals that I had. I was blessed because I did not have any deficits, but if you know someone whose life was dramatically changed after suffering a stroke, you should help him life have a life as normal as possible.\nThanks you for the question.\n-Puente"}
{"_id": "e2266812", "question": "How do you survive a stroke and recover completely as fast as possible?", "answers": "There is no fast recovery from a stroke. It causes brain damage from loss of oxygen to. part of the brain either from a blood clot that impedes blood flow or from a brain bleed that cuts off blood supply to the areas beyond the bleeding. The degree of damage depends on what part of the brain is affected and how long the area was without oxygen. Typically if your symptoms improve it will be within six months of the stroke. If the symptoms don’t improve in that time the damage will probably be permanent. Therapy can teach you how to adapt to your disability and help you learn new ways to do things."}
{"_id": "921bef3b", "question": "How long does it generally take to recover from stroke paralysis of one side of the body I'm 43", "answers": "Work at moving the paralyzed side. Movement typically starts small — the ability to make a fist. Work at it constantly while you are bored in bed or a wheelchair, whenever you are awake.\nWatch your hand as you try because vision can augment functions that were lost. When you can make a fist, try to bend your elbow or wrist. Try to touch your thumb to each finger. Remember “Eency weensie spider” hand movements\n? Try that. My mind remembered, but muscle memory was lost.\nI am in my 50’s, a bit older than you. If you were active and strong prior to the stroke, it may help you recover faster. Eat lots of fruit and vegetables, clean fish, and nuts. Nourish your body with a variety of whole unprocessed foods. Take medications as prescribed and monitor your blood pressure. Exercise as much as you can, as often as you can.\nSome exercises seem impossible at first, but you’ll be surprised how fast you improve if you keep trying. “Chair-ups” are done by lifting oneself with one’s arms without using your legs, while seated in a chair with strong arms. I could barely do one chair-up 8 weeks after my stroke, but I tried them 3x per day. 3 months after my stroke, I could do 10 chair-ups!"}
{"_id": "168e5cb7", "question": "Can cannabis help a stroke patient recover?", "answers": "My neurologist just addressed this very topic with me on my last visit a couple of weeks ago. He brought it up because he said he’d seen some of his MS patients get better with cannabinoids (not the smoked cannabis, but medical grade stuff without THC or something or the other). I was then, and remain skeptical about how it could help me. My response to him is that I understand that it’s helpful for people experiencing pain and discomfort, of which I have virtually none.\nSo my answer to you is that it depends. Consult a doctor, and if you can obtain some measure of recovery with it, why not? In my case, I’ve even stopped taking muscle relaxants and Botox injections because their effect wasn’t evident. If someone could show that it helps eliminate spasticity so that I can improve form on my affected side, of course I’ll consider it.\nYou didn’t mention if you’re a stroke patient or doing research. Either way, good luck. I’d be curious what else you find."}
{"_id": "6290d498", "question": "How long it takes for a person to recover from brain stroke?", "answers": "There is no long or short answer to this question as each stroke is unique; in that, no two individual strokes will affect a person the same!\nMy method is called Shak stroke therapy; I invented for my own father in 1986 purely to help him get well quicker than his physiotherapy was doing! His physiotherapist said it could take up to two years for him to be able to work again… I designed Shak therapy to help my father develop new neuro pathways at a much quicker rate and he was back at work after only 12 weeks… Since then I have developed shak therapy to a point where I have helped people recover fully, literally within minutes as you can see here on my youtube videos click here.\nNo actors are used in my videos. I have a book and video on sale at amazon\nexplaining exactly how to do Shak therapy The video has been circulating since about 2004 and has helped; countless number of people worldwide either fully recover or show improvement, where they thought, could never be any at all.\nWhen I do a shak therapy, I never know until I meet the person what condition they are in or what type of stroke they have had? I July 2018 I met a guy called Chris who had a stroke and could not raise his right are above his head, he allowed me to video him after his Shak therapy with me that lasted just a few minutes. here is the video click here\nthen there are some people who can take four or five shak therapies before any difference is show… each person is unique. as a footnote, To date; I have NEVER charged one single penny from anyone that I personally have done Shak therapy too. as (to me) each one is classed as an experiment; because I tweak and fine-tune different methods that I use to speed up the process even more and without lovely people putting their trust in me; there would be no Shak stroke therapy at all.\nI hope this has helped inspire you to try alternative methods that do work."}
{"_id": "a93433b2", "question": "Do you believe a person can recover from a major stroke? My husband suffered a massive stroke, a central main artery with occlusion stroke. I need some good hope as we face whatever is next.", "answers": "OK. Let’s try for some good hope.\nFirst, it’s impossible to say. The brain is quite plastic. It can’t repair itself, but it’s quite good at rewiring itself, working around injured areas and learning new functions when the previous brain areas aren’t able to perform them any more. The younger the person is, the more adaptable the brain is, but it’s still adaptable in people who are older. So there’s a reasonable/good possibility that your husband’s brain may be able to re-learn or adapt to his current condition.\nSecond, intensive rehabilitation can help, It’s best to begin as soon as possible and the most rapid progress is usually made in the first few months. On the other hand, progress can continue for years after the stroke or other brain injury.\nThird, huge advances are being made in bionics, electronics, and other sorts of devices to help brain injury patients both recover and function.\nNone of that is a guarantee of anything. But some people make remarkable recoveries, or at least great progress. And the more work the patient and the family put into it, the greater the likelihood of progress. One piece of advice: Don’t take a physician’s pronouncement of “He’ll never be able to….again” very seriously. While the physician may be correct, you don’t know unless/until you try.\nI interviewed the Pulitizer-prize winning columnist Art Buchwald several years after his massive stroke, and his progress was remarkable. And his isn’t an isolated story."}
{"_id": "0459eda3", "question": "Why is it so hard to recover mentally after a stroke?", "answers": "…it depends on a number of factors the most important being the type of stroke and the period between the stroke and the first administered medical aid.\nThe brain has a property known as plasticity which is the ability to repurpose other close by parts to perform other functions. This all takes a great deal of time and needs the correct environment, internal and externally for this to happen. So, eating well and excercising will help promote this. Equally so will trying to learn/development of cognitive activities; music playing, language learning, juggling, yoga, tia chi etc\nThe effects of a stroke last a lifetime and so does recovery. Being patient and determined to recover will lead to greater improvements. It will happen."}
{"_id": "bbf1a0d5", "question": "What factors make it likely to recover from stroke induced paralysis?", "answers": "I had a massive stroke in 2001 and lost all use of my right side my speech, and my right eye. Thankfully, I was young, 27, and I was told that would help in my recovery. It took almost 3 years of PT and occupational therapy to heal and recover almost all of my function. The brain does learn to find new pathways to send signals out to the body. It takes time. Lots of time.\nAs someone who had a stroke, I would like to tell you that your friends recovery can be frustrating for both of you.. She will need encouragement and yes, you'll have days where you have to push her harder than others and it will seem as if she is backsliding. Other days will be better for her. The best thing I can recommend, is to try to help her find as much humor in as many situations as you can. I've learned through many medical crises that laughter really does help your body to heal. It is better to laugh than to cry. Good luck."}
{"_id": "42245f4a", "question": "Can a person with a brain stem stroke recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f206866a", "question": "How well do infants \"handle\", or recover from stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "76e3ae58", "question": "What is the most important thing to keep in mind when recovering from a stroke - both for the person who had the stroke and those who support that person?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c2e1bf2c", "question": "What are your tips to help a loved one recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "215c04f8", "question": "Why can left-handed people recover from strokes fast?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6072358b", "question": "Can a person recover from the brain shifting after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dd3ac538", "question": "What are the chances of recovering from a massive stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "81c5009b", "question": "Can any person who is paralysed from his left side due to stroke recover fully? Can any stroke patient here share his/her stroke paralysis recovery journey? How much% have you recovered?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "22ac1acf", "question": "What is the best way to recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b1263759", "question": "What's the best and fastest way for me to recover from the stroke I suffered last year?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fc1e2e8d", "question": "What can I do to recover from a paralysis stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1298ca54", "question": "Should the people that died from a stroke after recovering from COVID-19 count as a COVID-19 victim?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "106459bd", "question": "What are the chances of recovery for patients suffering from a hemorrhagic stroke of the left side of the brain? By recovery, I am wondering how much of their motor, speech, and other skills they can recover?", "answers": "You will find out about 6 weeks to three months after the stroke. That is when most people reach their peak function post stroke. Small gains can be made for a few years after, but usually they are adaptive gains, by which I mean they've adopted a new way to do something rather than had a massive physical improvement.\nIts not the most pleasant to think about, and we always encourage hope and effort, but its important for families to be realistic, which means planning for life as it is now (at 6 weeks post) if gains happen thats great, if they don't they can be set up at home or residential care to cope with the new functional changes."}
{"_id": "73645e2e", "question": "Chance of recovery from second stroke. My father had a second right brain stroke. He was recovering a quite well from first stroke that he had second stroke. What is his chance of recovery to the point of such patients where he recovered last time?", "answers": "Unfortunately, the medical doctors don’t tell people how to properly recover from and prevent strokes. Medical/allopathic doctors are in the business of selling drugs. Natural cures cannot be patented, so the pharmaceutical industry suppresses natural cures because it cannot make money off of them.\nThere are natural ways of treating and preventing stroke. There’s a book called Prescription for Natural Cures, which you might want to look at. You could also consider taking your dad to a naturopathic doctor. The naturopathic doctors are replacing the medical doctors.\nkeep in mind that the proper way of curing, treating, and preventing disease requires lifestyle changes. It’s a fantasy to think that just popping a pill is going to cure chronic diseases. Your father will need to change his diet and take the proper supplements."}
{"_id": "3575bc45", "question": "If a stroke patient is not having any movement from the time of stroke and is in same condition for more than three months, will he be able to recover?", "answers": "This is me and supposedly I am still not recovered. My diagnosis is now semi-vegetative. I disagree with govt officials. I am not recovered to them, so your answer would be “no.”\nI disagree with them. I am obviously communicating with you. That means I have some movement. I do with my left arm. I’m using my left pointer finger to hit each key to type this to you.\nI do speak some, but at times can be unintelligible.\nI rely on typing things out to be understood.\nIt becomes what “recovered” means. If is “back to their old self,” then I am not. If it means “able to communicate and provide some care”, then I am. (I provide care by saying what to do. It’s like talking a plane down when there is no pilot.)\nMy stroke was in Dec 2002. What is occurring in me may not occur in others."}
{"_id": "74c54462", "question": "What is the best way to recover from stroke without treatment?", "answers": "Stroke is usually unprecedented and occurs due to disorientation in the nervous system attached to either brain or heart. Despite, availability of stroke treatments, some simple ways helped my relative quicken his post-stroke recovery process without any treatment. Keeping a healthy and stress-free lifestyle was one of his mantra for fast recovery. Some of the other ways that helped him recover without any stroke treatments were:\n-\nRegular meditation: Since meditation helps in reducing stress, increasing focus, keeping one calm along with improving the overall health, it truly works wonders during recovery.\n-\nHealthy diet: What you eat is what you become. For stroke recovery, the creation of neurons is important. Despite the doctor’s prescribed medications, the consumption of vitamins in the form of food like fish, pomegranate, nuts, seeds, blueberries, etc became effective stroke\ntreatment\n.\n-\nGood and enough sleep was another way to fasten the process of recovery for the brain."}
{"_id": "d23ae0f1", "question": "How long will it take an ischemic stroke to recover?", "answers": "An aneurism, called a stroke since olden days, when it was believed you were stricken by a supernatural deity, is a lack of blood getting to parts of the brain. “Ischaemic”, means lack of blood. Asking how long it takes to recover is totally dependent on how serious the aneurism is. Transient Ischaemic Attacks or TIA are relatively minor and effects last about 24 hours with no permanent damage, but aneurisms can also kill immediately. In between TIA and a killer attack are a whole range of aneurisms.\nFor anyone, who has a stroke, suitable pills will be prescribed and the patient may last as long as Kirk Douglas, who is about to turn 101 years old and who had an aneurism about 30 years ago."}
{"_id": "609eb2d0", "question": "Can fidget cubes help half body paralyzed stroke patients recover?", "answers": "I have had a major stroke and needed something to help me regain my fine motor skills. There weren't Fidget Cubes when I had my stroke and I wish there were. It's unfortunate that people are saying they wouldn't help. I know from experience that Fidget Cubes WOULD in fact assist with fine motor skills. I would think that questions like these should be answered by people with experience of having a stroke or physical therapists who specialize in recovery from strokes.\nFidget Cubes will not help you get your feeling back, obviously, but would assist in regaining your fine motor skills once you can start grasping items. I know when I was recovering at the rehab center, my therapist gave me all sorts of things to help. It was very difficult tending and releasing my hand grip. I would go to throw a ball, but my brain didn't send the message to release the ball when I was throwing it. Think of it like tricking your dog when you play fetch- that's what I kept doing.\nIt was also difficult to do everyday simple things we all take for granted like buttoning button. It took me years to regain this capability. Tying shoes. You'd think that's easy for someone that already knows how to tie a shoelace….but not after a stroke. I had to teach my hand to let go at the proper moment. Now, if you tie your shoe, really think about all the times you move your hands and all the times they released or loosing their grip. It's something that takes months to remaster after a stroke. So would Fidget Cubes help some with recovery of fine motor skills? The answer is yes. Thank you and this is in no way medical advice."}
{"_id": "0b556caf", "question": "How do I regain strength after I have recovered from stroke?", "answers": "Consistent use of the affected side. I had a stroke 18 years ago. I came home from the hospital in a wheelchair and 2 children. An infant and a 16 month old. Well, mommy shed that wheelchair as fast as I could. I had a purpose. My babies couldn’t take care of themselves. The more I did, the stronger I got. Four years post stroke I walked 60 miles in the Avon three day breast cancer walk!\nFunny how life changes. Now I’m getting severe arthritis in my unaffected hand. The affected hand HAS to do even more. One of the neatest observations I noted after my stroke was how my hands worked as a ‘team,’ when the left couldn’t function, the right would jump in and try to help his ‘friend.’ The right hand would actually instinctively reach over and try to do the work of the left side. I was constantly being told to put my unaffected hand down. I believe these days post stroke the unaffected side is restrained in order to MAKE the affected side work alone. I can see the benefits of this in therapy but long term I would’ve starved and I don’t think I would’ve recovered as quickly\nSo basically, what I am saying is the more you do for yourself the faster you will regain your strength. Do your exercises as prescribed. Work that affected side. But, do rest as much as necessary because when your brain takes such a ‘hit,’ the best medicine is to rest your brain. Rewiring pathways in your brain requires a lot of patience and energy.\nSlow and steady, you will get better. Just never ever give up. The brain is an amazing organ! Best wishes!"}
{"_id": "e5748c36", "question": "What can I do besides physiotherapy to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "I can only speak for what worked for me.\nAttitude is everything.\nI spent six months in rehab. The people who had strokes and had the attitude of “oh poor me, my life is over”, didnt progress a whole lot. The people who had the attitude of “ok, I am not staying like this, lets work on it” made a lot of progress.\nHowever, attitude has to come from within. One can certainly encourage a better attitude, but ultimately, it has to come from within.\nOther than the normal stuff the rehab professionals have you doing, this is what I did.\nI had one sided neglect. So I wore a watch on that side, to remind me that side was there.\nEveryday I had a trial size bottle of shampoo on the table. I would pick up my arm and close it around the bottle and try to lift it. Yes, it felt like it weighed 500lbs, but I eventually got it about 1/2 inch off the table. Took several months though.\nI worked really hard in rehab and gave every exercise 100% effort.\nWhen I went home, I continued with physio and did physio on my own.\nI got an exercise ball. I sat on it everyday. Then try to sit on it, without holding on. Eventually sit on it and left one leg. Does wonders for balance.\nTook me two years, but I got out of that wheelchair. Since the day I decided I dont need a chair, I never ever sat in it again. Ever. It is too easy to let yourself slide back, because it is easier.\nI accepted nothing less then becoming independent again. It is A LOT of work and can take a long time.\nLast year, 17 years post my last stroke, I hiked half of the camino frances. I still have issues, walk with a cane. Its all good, it could have ended up being so much worse and I thank my lucky stars that it isnt.\nATTITUDE."}
{"_id": "8b7165d1", "question": "Did you recover 100% from a stroke?", "answers": "Well, yes and no.\nNow, I had a stroke at birth. Due to my mother’s very high blood pressure, it was going to be either her or me. It was me. It affected me learning to walk on-time, hand-eye coordination and my speech were impacted. To this day, close to 41 years later, I still have poor hand-eye coordination, and when tired or when I try to run I drag my left leg behind me. Because of this issue, I never wanted to play in sports and hated physical education classes when young when I had to do physical things where others would notice how I ran, or my poor coordination. I’m not good at catching things. Now, I did learn how to skip, and I can skip along pretty fast. Not that it is a valuable life skill by any means.\nIn my stroke, my left side and speech had been impacted the most and it was my mother who ran my rehab program. “You want that toy? Well, you have to go get it yourself.” She told me that just last week, too. I’m kidding. Seriously, though, she worked with speech therapists to help me pronounce L’s properly, and the dreaded TH phonetic, and another letter or phonetic I’m forgetting. Thanks to my Mom and her hard work, I can speak eloquently and clearly. However, thanks to her Southern United States accent, and my Dad from Upstate New York I sound like I’m either from the Midwest area or Canada.\nI am now, thankfully, able to walk and talk and even at the same time. That may sound like a joke, but depending on the severity of the stroke that is a real issue not to be laughed at. I’m also very independent, able to drive, and I’m able to do as much as possible for myself as I’m also going through rehabilitation for my left shoulder after surgery."}
{"_id": "f7631767", "question": "Can someone that had a stroke, who can't talk, and move the right part of their body completely recover?", "answers": "Good therapy and strong will can go a long way toward improvement. Generally, however, a stroke needs to be intercepted with clot busting drugs within an hour of symptoms, unless it’s a hemorrhagic stroke, to minimize damage and improve outlook. Rehabilitation services can help minimize complications and may include working with:\na physical therapist to restore movement\nan occupational therapist to learn how to perform daily tasks, such as activities involving personal hygiene, cooking, and cleaning\na speech therapist to improve speaking ability\na psychologist to help cope with feelings of anxiety or depression"}
{"_id": "38cc38bd", "question": "How long would it take a 28-year-old to recover fully from stroke paralysis?", "answers": "Hi there, thank-you for the A2A and sorry for the delay in response.\nDue to the nature of stroke, and the many different symptoms it can present with depending on the region in which the stroke occurred it is difficult to put an exact time-frame on recovery.\nMultiple teams work together collaboratively using equipment, medication and physical treatment in order to regain function in the case of paralysis amongst other symptoms.\nFrom the physiotherapy point of view our main objectives are as follows:\nTo reduce any further adaptions of the body in terms of shortening of muscles, and reduced range of motion available at joints.\nTo maintain muscle conditioning in un-affected muscles\nTo encourage use of effected limbs, even if involuntary (manual manipulation)\nPhysiotherapy, as with other medical disciplines is most effective when implemented as early as possible.\nIn terms of long-term outcome from stroke, and how quickly someone may recover from paralytic effects depends on how quickly the above bullet-pointed are put into action alongside other factors such as patient compliance, and integration from the medical team re. medications and equipment.\nSome other factors determining prognosis are as follows:\nAge\nThe younger a person is, the more adaptable the brain is to recovery and therefore the better the prognosis\nPre-morbid activity levels\nIncreased activity and general fitness prior to stroke incident is a strong indicator for fast recovery\nEnvironment\nHow supportive family members are\nRecovery environment e.g. is the person on a specialist stroke ward?\nPharmacology\nHow well a person responds to certain drugs involved within the treatment of stroke.\nAs you can see it’s not very easy to apply a time scale to recovery as there are so many influencing factors, determining the extent to which recovery may or may not occur.\nIt is important to note that in most cases full recovery does not occur and people will be left with varying levels residual symptoms which may or may not impact everyday living.\nHowever discounting all of the above here is a simple template time frame for expected stroke recovery:\n6 weeks\nThe most intense period of treatment in order to make full use of the adaptability of the brain and neurons in within the early period\n3 months\nMost recovery gains will be achieved within this period and physiotherapy will remain an integral factor during this period\n6 months\nMost of the recovery which will be achieved will have occurred by now but it not unsaid that minor gains can still occur for up to 2 years.\nHope this gives you a basic picture as to what you could expect to see recovery wise in terms of time frame and the factors influencing prognosis.\nThank-you once again for the A2A (it helps with my studies to re-evaluate what I have learnt). :)"}
{"_id": "ec4d545d", "question": "Can antidepressants help in recovering memory and language skills after a stroke?", "answers": "There is some mild evidence that SSRI’s (paxil, lexapro etc) may help facilitate with recovery after a stroke. I do not think it is an overwhelming help, unfortunately. Treating post-stroke depression is also an important goal in itself."}
{"_id": "43bad3c1", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a cerebellar stroke?", "answers": "From my personal perspective, no: but I have made vast improvements in the last 20 years. I was a foreign language instructor, mainly in Spanish, so being speechless is rather self-conscious for me, especially in being a teacher. I still have aphasia but I've “fully\" recovered considering that the stroke was a fluke: no prescriptions (as of now even though I was at least on 15 medications fed through my stomach tube which lasted for about 6 months), no high blood pressure, and certainly not the obesity factor. So keep on living, my friend…never give up!"}
{"_id": "7bc7be0d", "question": "Is sudden trouble with vision from one or both eyes normal while recovering from a stroke?", "answers": "I had a white light spectrum aura in an almost 45 degree angle in both eyes. It came about 3 to 4 days after the stroke, and lasted almost 2 weeks. That was due to the inflammation and edema, and the pressure it creates after the stroke. That’s how my arm and leg got progressively worse AFTER the stroke, too. A delay of 3 weeks before the final symptoms “set”. I finally noticed how bad it was when taking a shower and couldn’t lift my arm above my shoulder (got home slept mostly, really tired so didn’t notice). Too stiff to raise.\nSo despite the stroke happening weeks before, stroke damage can and does continue due to the inflammation/edema/pressure that occurs after the stroke. That’s the white haze you see in MRIs. The original lesion looks more like a peanut for a lacunar lesion or walnut (or larger) for a larger stroke in size.\nMRI/CT of a lesion area looks like this about 3 days later…\nNotice the white field? That’s the inflammation and edema that comes after a stroke. While that inflammation and edema exists damage continues due to the pressure it causes in the area. In 6 weeks only a faint white field exists.\nIn the newer MRIs with higher resolutions the details of a fresh lesion can be seen. Why I describe mine as looking like a walnut in it’s shape, size and creases (I was in the ER in less than 15 minutes after the stroke). 3–4 days later MRI can’t even see the lesion anymore due to the white field.\nSo that is WHY you can have vision problems even weeks after a stroke. More inflammation and edema builds up, the pressure it creates, causes it to press against the CN nerves, and if it’s mid-brain stroke, the Thalamus LGN and Corona Radiations can be affected.\nIt’s eerie seeing like the Pink Floyd’s Dark Side of the Moon album cover before your eyes, and seeing the “light” scatter like atoms under a MRI. Then to have it all disappear leaving a water drop like scotoma that remains permanent."}
{"_id": "cb641a5c", "question": "Can a baby recover from a stroke?", "answers": "I have treated stroke patients successfully…but all of them have been aged…\nWhat age is baby…?\nCraniofacial and Craniosacral massage therapy…does have a positive healing impact…\nWelcome to connect with me for healing support…"}
{"_id": "521efcec", "question": "How do I recover a lost memory from a brain stroke?", "answers": "This is a A2A so I will do my best. When I had my stroke, I was in a parking lot 50 miles away from home. But, what I remember is, I was watching a movie in my house with my Girlfriend. I then woke up in an ICU with a tube down my throat. I tried to pull the tube out because I had no idea what had happened (Car wreck, explosion ect.) and the staff were calling me Bob (No one calls me Bob it’s kind of a thing) so I thought something must have happened to my Girlfriend since she would have told them never to call me Bob.\nThey had to tie me down and heavily sedate me. They could not figure out what was wrong with me. Unbeknownst to me, my GF had been there many times I had just not been awake. Well one night I woke up and on the white board, in my GF’s handwriting was the message “Don’t call him Bob. His name is Robert.”\nWell I settled down immediately because I knew my Girlfriend ok.\nSo to answer the question. I lost 3 days before my stroke. I remember nothing. When I had the stroke, I was robbed (That’s a different story) so I was able to track my iphone and answer some questions. However, no matter how many people I talk to, I remember not a thing. Sorry.\nI like to say that the worst thing about having a stroke is, until you try to remember it, you don’t know what you’ve forgotten. Sometimes it’s an Actors name or just the correct word. For the most part, however, except for those 3 days, I do eventually remember."}
{"_id": "03cb372c", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a minor stroke if the person can talk, walk and lost no function?", "answers": "I had my fist series of strokes on January 31, 2020 and I was 60, but a “very young looking and hard to believe 60 yr old” female. I was getting dressed that morning as I had the day off and I began having an ocular migraine but without any headache. They call them ocular auras and I began having those several years prior with a diagnosis of “nothing can be done and just deal with them”. Over the past two years prior the auras got increasingly frequent and longer, often up to 45 minutes but I sucked it up and learned to keep working while they were happening, Unknown to anyone who may have been around me had no idea I was experiencing one. That morning was a quick aura when I reached to pick up my cell phone my left hand would not work. Hmm I thought this was a bit odd so I picked it up with my right hand and tried to text my hubby and was unable to distinguish the icons on the phone. As 20 minutes passed I awoke my son and asked him to help me find the icon on my phone so I could call his father and he looked at me with an oddity replying what do you mean you can’t find the keypad because you use your phone constantly. He immediately had me do the Stroke symptom indicators and saw nothing odd so we passed it off as an oddity. About half hour later I decided to drive over to my hubby’s work a bit earlier than planned for our lunch date and while on the highway I got very confused at the traffic lights and my vision began having black out spots. I have never experienced that type of confusion. I managed to pull into a strip mall center and sat there until nausea overwhelmed me. Still not really grasping what was happening, after the nausea subsided I proceeded to try and make my way to my hubby’s work place but continued to experience the same confusion symptoms. I managed to get to his work with the confusion but still partially mentally aware. When I walked into his office he took one look at me and told me I was having or had had a stroke. Off to the ER, all sorts of testing, diagnosis was a series of 4 strokes over that two hour span of time. BTW, the MRI brought on claustrophobia which I’ve never thought I had. Stayed in hospital for 2 days, left with meds and NO determination on where the stroke originated from. Cholestrol was off the charts as well. Went back to work 4 days later with inability to use my left hand and missing spots in my vision. No one knew but my boss. I was VERY Lucky! Today, after a year, I feel pretty normal and can use my left hand almost 100%, but vision loss spots are permanent. I’ve lost 30 lbs, greatly improved my cholesterol numbers, eat only chicken, fish, fruits and yogurt, lol and walk 2–4 miles everyday. It’s been a lifestyle change but I still think about and fear another stoke everyday. The first 8 months the stroke fear consumed me and I’m still in fear but have managed to let go of the stress, appreciate my day to day living and enjoy every minute I can, thankful to still be here. I wrote this because I still feel the odd things from having had stroke but to encourage you to not ignore the symptoms. I had them all, high cholesterol, middle age belly fat, tingling in my left hand and face and lips, but blew it off because I was too busy taking care of everyone and everything. I miss the old me, but a new me emerged and thank the Lord there must be a reason he spared me."}
{"_id": "0ec3e5d8", "question": "How long will it take to recover from stroke due to blood loss?", "answers": "It will take as long as it takes. A stroke is serious in itself but with the blood loss they have to stabilize your physical condition first. After the doctors do that, they have to assess you to determine what caused the events ( the stroke and blood loss) fix those problems and determine what damage was done. Then they will try to help you recover the faculties you may have lost due to the event.\nRehabilitation depends on the type of damage done , the severity of the damage, and the strength and will of the patient. There is no set time period for rehabilitation. The therapists will work with the patient until they feel he has recovered as many of his faculties as he is able or until the patient’s insurance cuts off coverage.\nEveryone PLEASE remember that you CAN appeal insurance denials."}
{"_id": "857bdfc1", "question": "How do I recover speech after a brain stroke?", "answers": "Short-Term Therapy May Help Speech\nIn the study, researchers examined the effects of a short-term, intensive round of speech therapy in 27 stroke survivors who had suffered from language impairment for about four years.\nEach of the stroke survivors received 30 hours of language training three hours a day for 10 days; their language skills were assessed before and immediately after the training as well as six months later.\nThe results appear in the June edition of Stroke.\nThe speech therapy used a technique called constraint-induced aphasia therapy or CIAT, which combines intense verbal communication training with language games that build simple as well as complex language skills.\nThe technique encourages stroke patients to speak rather than using gestures as their primary means of communication.\nThe results showed that language skills improved significantly in 85% of the stroke patients after the intensive speech therapy, and those improvements were sustained for six months.\nResearchers also found that the improvement occurred regardless of the stroke survivor's age or the severity of his or her language impairment.\nIn addition, the study showed that 15 stroke patients who received additional language training, which was reinforced by family members and friends, showed further improvements.\nThe psychologist applies a combination of non-invasive methods (fMRI– functional magnetic resonance imaging and TMS – transcranial magnetic stimulation) to deduce what happens in the brain during the test. “We thus proved that the left hemisphere, as expected, was activated during speech production, while the right hemisphere did not actively contribute to language function”, explains Hartwigsen. This is the regular functionality within a healthy brain. From these results as well as others, scientists had up to now deduced that the right hemisphere did not contribute to speech production in the healthy system and was therefore suppressed."}
{"_id": "80717499", "question": "Is it possible for a 50 year old woman to fully recover after being paralyzed due to brain stroke for 5 years?", "answers": "Is this woman receiving physical therapy? Are her muscles being passively exercised? Both of these would improve chances of any degree of recovery. What has she been doing the past 5 years. Were both sides of her body involved (which would place the stroke in a different location than if only one side is impaired)? All this information is critical in determining prognosis\nTo understand motor recovery, lets look at the worst case scenario,-Hemispherectomy- where half the brain is removed due intractable epilepsy,\nImmediately after surgery, the entire opposite half of the body is paralyzed.\nExtensive therapy begins almost immediately.\nThe younger the person is at the time of surgery, (typically infants) the better the recovery, Walking seems to be the first to improve. Some use of the arm follows. Fine motor coordination (fingers) seems impaired or lacking, even in children. In some cases,. the arm may be able to help in very simple tasks,. In others, it remains limp at the side.\nThe adult brain is less plastic than the child's and the final result may not be as satisfactory.\nChristopher Reeve, who was paralyzed at the neck, described a procedure frequently used in rehab, in which the patient is placed in a body harness and suspended from the ceiling over a treadmill. He is positioned so that his feet touch the treadmill.\nWhen the motor is turned on and the platform begins to move), the feet show reflexive walking behavior (this is organized in the spinal cord). This type of activity maintains muscle tone in the legs (should any small reco9very occur, the leg muscles will not have atrophied) and also is related to a spontaneous ability for the patient to go into reflexive motion when standing on a regular floor\nCurrent research in restoration of motor function also involves the implantation of electrodes into the muscles and stimulating them electrically. Signals to implement motion are taken directly from the patients brain"}
{"_id": "ea6ad38a", "question": "How do people feel and what do they think about while recovering from a stroke?", "answers": "First month: I’m going to rehab so hard that I’ll be better in a month! I’m going to crush it!\nsecond - sixth months: Whoa. I’m exhausted. I still want to get better, but I must pace myself.\nsixth - twelfth month: I’m no good to anybody like this. I’d rather kill myself than go through any more rehab. Please just let me die =(\ntwelth month - fifth year: yeah, this pretty much sucks.\nFifth year - tenth year: this definitely sucks.\ntenth year - present: I’ve discovered a therapy that may actually work. I have felt at normal energy for weeks at a time. Then it stopped working. =( I’ve gone back to my doc for touch-ups, which work for a little while, and then I’m exhausted again.\ni just want to feel normal. I want to be able to go to the amusement park with my daughter and not be dead for a week afterwards. I’d like to go on a date to the theater with DH and not be terrified that getting home at 11pm will wreck me the following day. I want to (literally) dream. I want to help my husband around the house. I want to buy a shower organizer online and not be subject to a million questions like, “Did you read the reviews?” When it arrives and doesn’t come with suction cups. I was just too tired to do so. It sounds really pathetic after 13 years =("}
{"_id": "7e26cc4b", "question": "What is the a way to recover after having a stroke?", "answers": "Strokes (the \"brain attack\" variety) have diverse manifestations, ranging from no effect to life threatening illness. Thus, there is no one answer to this question.\nAssuming a degree of disability, the following are likely to improve recovery:\n1. rapid hospitalisation (after onset) with \"clot buster\" treatment in appropriate cases <reduce severity of disability>\n2. management in an organised stroke unit, with input from appropriate therapists <maximise recovery>\n3. a positive bent of mind (easier said than done) with family support and psychologist input if needed - this is akin to steady training like marathon runners do <psychological health is essential to any form of training>\n4. it is important to continue prescribed medications to reduce risk of future stroke. No medications known to improve recovery from a stroke that has already occurred.\nClearly, these are generic principles and may not apply for your particular situation.\nDo get specialist input if you haven't already.\nGood luck."}
{"_id": "f62e6577", "question": "Is there any stem cell treatment or anything that can be done to reverse the damage caused by a hemmoragic stroke?", "answers": "Sorry. At the present state ofstem cell therapy the neurological damage you May have suffered is permanent."}
{"_id": "e84a8ce3", "question": "What is the best way to recover from a stroke if one side is weak and the knees knock because of it?", "answers": "Neurological rehabilitation is the best approach to improving functionality and mobility after a stroke. Rehab hospitals generally have an outpatient rehab group to help stroke patients continue recovering after discharge from acute rehab.\nPart of the problem may be that the stroke survivor doesn’t feel where his/her knees are. That ability is called “proprioception.” I had a problem like that with an ankle. It would roll and unless I was looking in a mirror, I couldn’t tell. Initially, I used a brace. I strengthened the ankle and didn’t need the brace after a while, but walking barefoot in the house, my ankle rolled, I didn’t realize and put my full weight on the foot, breaking two of the long bones (2nd & 3rd metatarsals).\nStrengthening and weight bearing through the joints will help, but take it slowly and be careful! I should not have been walking around barefoot."}
{"_id": "625ddb86", "question": "Have you ever had a stroke and completely recovered?", "answers": "A person who had a stroke never “completely recovers”. A lesion causes damage. They can recover if their stroke avoided critical areas of the brain, to the point they are functional, and can return to many of their interests again. It’s like a broken leg. The bone will heal, yet they may walk with a limp afterwards.\nEven the mildest strokes offers challenges to work around the damage. Some minor strokes can actually have some serious syndromes; while massive strokes may be limiting only to movement or speech.\nWhile every human is from the same species, anatomically we are varied. Blood vessels can grow differently, as well as pathways in the brain can. Check the veins in your hands. Compare it even with a sibling. Notice they’re different? Which is why when a stroke happens in two people with the exact same type of stroke, each can have two different outcomes. A lesion in XYZ area may have missed a pathway in patient A due to anatomical variance; while in patient B it landed squarely on it and is really debilitated.\nWhat matters is WHAT was damaged, and working around that damage. That’s work around is called, neuroplasticity, a bridging to other areas of the brain that, though cruder, can restore some/most function again.\nWhen I had my stroke my vision was damaged. Everything was like seeing things under water. Then days later half my vision was replaced with a white light spectrum in both eyes. I was scared I would go blind. It eventually faded away and left a water spot type scar and visual snow. I lost my night vision, too. Over time, and use, my vision is well enough that I don’t walk into walls. Those changes were possible by neuroplasticity (the saying of “use it or lose it” is true with brain traumas. More you use the function the more the brain will compensate for the loss). What is gained isn’t what the person had before, but the person can return to things they once did again, if their stroke didn’t land on ground zero. Some changes are permanent, but a lot can return with rehab."}
{"_id": "f75da206", "question": "Some astrologer said that my aunt will not be able to recover from Brain Stroke (dementia). What should we do?", "answers": "I realize that there are many good astrologers in India and that it is a respected profession there but this is not something an astrologer can help you with.\nForget the astrologer. The astrologer has no idea.\nDiscuss this with a good doctor. There are many good doctors all over India.\nStroke and dementia are two different illnesses. Both need medical intervention. Not an astrologer.\nTake care\nJon"}
{"_id": "459ffb50", "question": "How can stroke victims recover? Where are the best hospitals to treat stroke victims?", "answers": "While rehab centers and hospitals can be very helpful for those recovering from strokes, rehabilitation - such as physical, occupational, and speech therapy - can often occur at home, depending on the severity of the stroke, type(s) of disability, and community resources.\nThe best hospital for treating acute strokes, on the other hand, is often the CLOSEST one, assuming they have a neurologist available with experience diagnosing and treating strokes. The long-term prognosis for those with strokes is greatly improved by urgent treatment, provided within minutes to hours of symptom onset.\nTreatments often are available to dissolve or remove the offending clot that is causing an ischemic stroke (damage from oxygen deprivation to part of the brain, usually when a blood vessel is blocked by a clot). Other strategies may be used to stop bleeding during a much less common hemorrhagic stroke (caused by a ruptured blood vessel in the brain).\nBut any of these treatments must be provided very, very quickly. Lost minutes mean lost brain function.\nIf you or someone you are with seems to be having a stroke, with sudden numbness and/or weakness (often one-sided), slurred speech, confusion, dizziness, loss of coordination, vision changes, very severe headache, or other new neurologic symptoms, call an ambulance immediately. Don’t try to transport yourself or the other person to the hospital. Call an ambulance to get help right away and treatment started as soon as possible."}
{"_id": "4d1bda62", "question": "How does the brain recover from a stroke. I know people learn to talk again. Does the brain need to be retaught from scratch?", "answers": "NO SOME STROKES ARE WORSE THAN OTHERS AND HOW QUICKLY THEY GET HELP DETERMINES THE SEVERITY AND THE SPEED OF THE RECOVERY AND TO WHAT EXTENT THE RECOVERY IS BUT I KNOW PEOPLE WHO HAVE HAD STROKES AND WASNT FOUND FOR OVER 24 HRS AND WERE ONLY IN HOSPITAL FOR A FEW DAYS AND ONLY HAD A SLURRED SPEACH AND A FACE THAT DROPPED DOWN ONE SIDE BUT WERE STILL VERY AWARE AND FULLY FUNCTIONAL BRAIN WISE WITHIN DAYS AND WHO'S FACE AND SPEACH WENT BACK TO NORMAL WITHIN A FEW MONTHS AND ARE NOW BACK TO NORMAL AFTER LESS THAN 6 MONTHS BUT WERE ALWAYS STILL THEMSELVES THROUGHOUT BUT WAS BAD WITHIN THE FIRST FEW DAYS OF IT HAPPENING BUT I'VE ALSO KNOWN PEOPLE WHO HAD A STROKE AND WERE GIVEN TREATMENT IMMEDIATELY AND HAVE STILL NOT FULLY RECOVERED YEARS LATER AND STILL HAVE SLURRED SPEACH AND A DROOP ON ONE SIDE OF THEIR FACE SO IT ALL DEPENDS ON THE AGE AND HEALTH OF THE PERSON BEFORE IT HAPPENS WHEN IT HAPPENS AND AFTER IT HAPPENS AND THE CAUSE AND SEVERITY OF THE STROKE THEY HAVE ASWELL AS THE SPEED IN WHICH THEY ARE TREATED BY MEDICAL EXPERTS BUT IVE NOT KNOWN OF ANY THAT HAS TO LEARN HOW TO TALK ALL OVER AGAIN BUT THERE MAY BE CASES WHERE SOME DO BUT MOST ARE STILL ABLE JUST NOT AS WELL AS BEFORE FOR A WHILE USUALLY A SHORT WHILE AND THEIR BRAINS STILL USUALLY WORK NORMALLY SHORTLY AFTER HAVEING ONE BUT AS I SAID SOME ARE MORE SEVERE THAN OTHERS AND THE AGE AND OVERALL HEALTH OF THE PERSON AT THE TIME OF THE STROKE IS PARAMOUNT"}
{"_id": "ff25a00a", "question": "What is it like to have a major stroke and recover?", "answers": "Recovery is a long process — my brain hemorrhage was 4 1/2 years ago and I’m still doing my PT exercises every day. I expect I’ll continue to do therapy for the rest of my life because if I stop working at recovery, my recovery stops.\nI was in the ICU for two weeks and in acute care another six weeks for rehab. After that, I had six weeks of in-home therapy before “graduating” to outpatient therapy. Until COVID, I did a few weeks of therapy every few months to update my program.\nAmazingly, I’m walking and using both hands, though the affected side is clumsy. I credit my therapists with my recovery. I thought I’d never walk again or be able to care for myself.\nI was out of work for five months, then tried to return, working part-time for a year before my doctors told me it was too much for me. I’m now on disability.\nBuy disability insurance! SSDI is not much and it takes forever to qualify, even when one has a medical file as comprehensive as mine. Disability is more common than early death, so disability insurance is as important as life insurance. I’d gotten a policy decades ago and it paid off. I am grateful I don’t have to worry about income."}
{"_id": "067526a9", "question": "Has Joe Biden fully recovered from his two brain hemorrhages? Are Biden’s strokes dangerous for our national security?", "answers": "Another worthless troll question. Quora should really be shutting down these far right trolls, because it degrades the whole site. Please report and downvote the question - it assumes facts which are not in evidence.\nAt least President Biden can walk down a ramp unassisted, and pick up a glass of water with just one hand."}
{"_id": "4238caa1", "question": "How long will it take my husband to recover from 3 strokes? He cannot sit, stand, walk or talk.", "answers": "Wish I could give you a better answer than William provided, but the truth is after 3 strokes full recovery is not realistic. Aggressive therapy and compliance with medication and dietary recommendations give him the best chance for quality of life. In general , based on his current status I would anticipate a few weeks in acute rehab followed by a few months of subacute either at home or rehab center. If he responds to that will probably require 3 or more months of outpatient therapy.Sending prayers for you and him. Please consider joining a support group to help you navigate this journey."}
{"_id": "2a0a9a3d", "question": "What are some good ways to help someone recover brain function after a stroke?", "answers": "What are some good ways to help someone recover brain function after a stroke?\nI’m not a neurologist and never had a stroke.\nSo what am I doing here?\nI’m told my brain injury rehab was not dissimilar from some stroke rehab protocols. I trust folks with personal or professional stroke experience will write answers and also let me know what I got wrong and what’s missing.\nUsually, people who’ve stroked work on cognitive issues with neurologists; mental health professionals; cognitive rehabilitation therapists; speech and language therapists; and occupational therapists.\nI suffered an acquired brain injury nine years ago. I worked with all of the above - and each professional also provided services to stroke survivors.\nI was incredibly fortunate and recovered ~ 90%.\nI found a few good (audio*) books with helpful cognitive exercises, tips to accommodate my deficits, and at least one about adjusting to - and grieving - my new normal.\nSupportive friends and family, meeting others in my situation, and therapy were invaluable. As was Jim. And the dogs.\nWe tagged that experience as “the time when mommy’s brain fell out”. Pretty catchy, right?\n*I never recovered my ability to read. I miss holding books - though Audible must appreciates my deficit:)\nI previously wrote about my brain injury in these posts:\nAmy E. Brown's answer to Why is it so difficult for some people to seek therapy for brain processing issues?\nAmy E. Brown's answer to Are we sure that ADD/ADHD can't be acquired as an adult?"}
{"_id": "06ab8ca3", "question": "Do the microvessels and other aspects of the Blood Brain Barrier repair themselves, regenerate, and/or recover fully if they are physically damaged by events, including, but not limited to,stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d96a6f03", "question": "How much water is too much when recovering from a heat stroke?", "answers": "I agree with Dr. Jay. Heatstroke is something totally different from heat exhaustion or simple dehydration.\nThe amount of time spent in the intensive care unit really depends on the severity of the “stroke”. Individuals with pre-existing heart or kidney disease will spend longer in the ICU than those without these issues.\nClose monitoring is essential by both the nursing and medical staff. In order to manage fluid requirements closely, both fluid input and output will be determined and charted, labs monitored, and physical exam changes consistent with fluid overload noted — many times a day if required. The patient will typically be restricted as to how much fluid is taken by mouth. Patients permitted to drink ad lib can develop water intoxication resulting in cerebral edema, which if it happens, places the patient in dire straits, indeed.\nResponses should be considered general in nature, and not specific to any one person; consequently, they are not to be construed as specific medical advice and do not create a doctor/patient relationship. For more specific advice unique to your particular situation, consult a local medical professional."}
{"_id": "d78e6f6b", "question": "How do I recover my mom from stroke paralysis in the past year?", "answers": "Recovery from stroke paralysis depends on degree of paralysis and underlying health condition. Also timely treatment of stroke also helps in limiting the degree of paralysis and thus helps faster recovery.\nIn this case the paralysis is a year old. You have not mentioned whether any physical rehabilitation have been done till date. Most important in such cases is to perform limb movements active or passive depending on severity of paralysis. For this in your case home based physiotherapy program will be suitable.\nAlso it is important to prevent stroke recurrence by keeping Diabetes and blood pressure under control."}
{"_id": "a77cdcf7", "question": "What can a woman in her 70s use as a peg tube for water and nutritional drinks to cure her diabetes, arteriosclerosis, and recover from a stroke?", "answers": "There is diet which is effective in treating cardiovascular diseases and diabetes at the same time. Dr. Caldwell Esselstyn, Director of Cardiovascular Disease Prevention and Reversal Program at the Cleveland Clinic has reversed arterial plaque buildup in his patients by putting them on whole-food (not refined or processed) plant-based (WFPB) diet. Below is a angiographic imaging evidence of reversal of plaque buildup in coronary artery of one of his patients by going on WFPB diet. Image A is before going on WFPB diet, and image B is after being on WFPB diet for 32 months. You can see that severe plaque buildup has been removed from the coronary artery after being on WFPB diet.\nThis is opposite to what many doctors believe, which is that coronary artery diseases can not be reversed and one needs to take medication for rest of the life and if the condition becomes severe, the person needs to have surgical intervention. But the above evidence shows it otherwise.\nFormer president Clinton had quadruple bypass surgery and he was still having problems. He went on WFPB diet as per advices of Dr. Esselstyn and Dr. Dean Ornish and he is fine now (He has also lost weight). He credits that diet to him still being alive today\nThe WFPB diet includes vegetables, beans, fruits, and whole grains, but excludes meat, fish, eggs and dairy. Also no processed foods or added sugar (need to read labels as items may contain processed ingredients or fructose corn syrup etc). Esselstyn recommends little or no oil as it is an extract of food and thus not whole food. For those, who have had prior cardiac event (for example, stroke or heart attach), he recommends not to comsume oil at all. (One needs to take Vitamin B12 supplements, as both, those on plant-based diet and those who are omnivores, have been found to be Vitamin B12 deficient, more so for plant-based group, as their foods are generally not fortified with B12 supplements).\nDr. Esselstyn has followed 200 patients, who had prior cardiac event. He put them on WFPB diet. About 90 percent of patients fully complied with the diet and they did not have subsequent cardiac event over the years. Of the 10 percent who did not comply, 65 percent had subsequent cardiac events.\nThe WFPB diet has also been used to reverse diabetes. Dr. Neal Barnard, an NIH diabetes researcher and a professor at George Washington University School of Medicine has reversed diabetes in his research studies and in his patients by changing their diet to WFPB. The following video link is a very informative and interesting presentation by him about cellular level mechanism of insulin resistance and how diet can reverse the insulin resistance and thus diabetes. The cause of the insulin resistance is fat in the muscle cells, and the whole food plant based diet (no meat, fish, eggs or dairy and little or no oil) reduces this muscle cell fat theirby reversing type 2 diabetes. In a study, the whole food plant based diet with little oil reduced HgA1c levels better than diet recommended by ADA (Americans Diabetic Association). This diet also reduces weight without counting calories. I know a couple of people, who based on such a diet, have seen positive results in terms of weight loss (without counting calories) and their HbA1c levels.\nPeople often control the symptoms of diabetes by reducing carbs consumption, but it is the fat in muscle cell, which stops cells from metabolizing blood sugar. Thus one needs to reduce this muscle cell fat to reduce the cellular level insulin resistance to reverse the diabetes, rather than always trying to control the symptoms by limiting carbs. (For example, fiber is very important in controlling and reversing diabetes and fiber is a carbohydrate. All vegetables are carbohydrates. Although, one needs to avoid refined and processed carbs). Here is a video link for the presentation by Dr. Barnard. Very informative.\nThe same diet also has effect on type 1 diabetes. The following figure shows reduction in insulin dose for both type of diabetes upon changing the diet (to whole food plant based diet) only for few days.\nYou will see people often recommend low carb high fat diet for diabetes, but it not only does not reverse diabetes as explained above, the high fat diet can be bad for cardiovascular health. While the above diet (whole-food plant-based diet with very little oil) is heart-healthy as discussed above.\nHere are some expert opinions (such as American Heart Association, American Cancer Society, American Hea, American Dietetic Association, American Medical Association, etc.) on dangers of low-carb, high-fat or high-protein diet.\nhttp://atkinsexposed.org/Opinion...\nReferences for the above figure:\nBarnard RJ, Lattimore L, Holly RG, et al. “Response of non-insulin-dependent diabetic patients to an intensive program of diet and exercise.” Diabetes Care 5 (1982): 370–374.\nBarnard RJ, Massey MR, Cherny S, et al. “Long-term use of a high-complex-carbohydrate, high-fiber, low-fat diet and exercise in the treatment of NIDDM patients.” Diabetes Care 6 (1983): 268–273\nAdditional Information: Here is a CNN report by Dr. Sanjay Gupta on President Clinton’s heart issues and how he overcame it with Esselstyn’s diet. Very interesting. There is an interview with Dr. Esselstyn and Dr. Dean Ornish. It also shows a test that is effective in predicting future cardiovascular events."}
{"_id": "d68760cf", "question": "How can someone recover from partial brain damage due to stroke?", "answers": "Hello, I am also sorry to hear about your issue, and I deeply hope it will improve as soon as possible.\nPlease refer to my answer here:\nWhat are new treatment options for stroke recovery for teenage survivors when botox and physiotherapy are not improving mobility or stability?\nI hope this helps!\nAlso,\nBest regards and all the best!"}
{"_id": "c3571ada", "question": "Can a patient still recover after a left brain stroke?", "answers": "Depending on the severity and region affected; patient’s health and personality, “recovery” will come in stages. Priority is to get them mobile and to be independent in their care as much as possible.\nThat priority of walking again sometimes causes problems later, as the window of opportunity for neuroplasticity (the body’s ability to use secondary areas of the brain to compensate and work around brain injured infarct[s]) to work is generally 1 year (it’s longer than a year, but faster a stroke survivor retrains from a loss of function, the better the outcomes are — i.e., walking/gait rehab over hand/arm therapy as a priority, is a problem in stroke recovery and why so many can walk again, but their hand/arm maybe paralyzed and speech therapy isn’t the priority before moving out of bed).\nMCA strokes (more common in the West) mostly occur in the Left Hemisphere, as the body tries to protect it’s Right Hemisphere (where cognition/executive function is located, and so essential to survive). The location of MCA strokes also places it near the Broca’s area of the brain responsible for speech. Why so many MCA stroke survivors have the tell-tale F.A.S.T stroke signs (“S” being speech impairment).\nMy grandfather had a MCA stroke and they told him he would never walk again. Wrong talk! Before he died, grandpa was walking with a cane again and driving himself around like before. That was in the 1970s. Rehab today is 10x better than that, and they get patient up and moving in just days.\nIt won’t be a “miracle” recovery (neuroplasticity relies on using secondary area[s] of the brain to regain use of affected areas of the brain again), but they can recover enough to return to their life as before."}
{"_id": "906f9b4d", "question": "My mom is just recovering from stroke, beside physio-therapy what else could she do to recover fully quickly?", "answers": "Do the PT exercises religiously at least twice each day. I have also been swimming, which helps my affected arm. Stretching helps as well."}
{"_id": "7757ae6d", "question": "Can I still compete in boxing after recovering from a stroke?", "answers": "Its very unlikely you would pass a fighter’s physical and find some doctor to sign off on you boxing as an amateur or pro fighter in any type of fighting if you have had a stroke. I would not even let you work out in my gym or school if that was the case because the risk is too great and liability wise if something was to happen then I would be on the hook for a serious lawsuit from your heirs.\nI actually have been in that situation where a student working out developed problems and died enroot to the hospital in the ambulance. Luckily I had done everything including making him get a doctor’s clearance to resume working out before this happened. The lawyers and his family had no place to go legally because of that and suing me which they were considering doing. While I also had insurance for this that insurance does not cover negligence on my part and that is what it would have been if I had not made him get that medical clearance given the medical issues he had earlier when he first started working out at my school."}
{"_id": "024cfafb", "question": "How do I cope w/ my boyfriend being more attentive, affectionate, and loving to our dog than me while I try to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Boys always love their dogs more than girls. Reason is, as girls, given an opportunity, we would stress them out so much with our demands and we do appear too needy at times.\nMany girls are even be highly dependent on their boyfriends and in fact many make boyfriends for the same reason.\nBut dogs are so cute, adorable, always loving and affectionate, always giving more love and loyalty to boys, never very demanding, enjoy time endlessly with boys.\nThat may be the reason that your boyfriend loves his dog and wants to give more time to his dog. But if you need care and he doesn't care for you, we can't attribute it to his love and attention for his dog. It's you. Maybe it's time for you to move on? Think about it. Maybe all your boyfriend needs is peace and love with his dog and he doesn't find that good connection with you anymore. You might want to rethink your relationship because if he is not caring for you but has time for someone else, you might be left alone sooner than you. It's better to be prepared than to be sorry in life."}
{"_id": "9b629a42", "question": "Do stroke patients recover after two years?", "answers": "The maximum recovery in function occurs in first six months to an year after stroke, thereafter the recovery process slows down"}
{"_id": "977701ad", "question": "How painful is the process of physical therapy when recovering from a stroke?", "answers": "Stroke attack is the third leading disease which causes of death in the United States, It is very serious and long term disability in adults and stroke can happen to anyone at any time but mostly women have more stroke problem than a man in the United States.\nWhen a blood vessel in the brain is blocked at that time you face the situation of stroke and it is also called a cerebral vascular accident(CVA). There are two types of stroke ischemic stroke and hemorrhagic which I have seen commonly in every people.\nPhysical therapy is very useful for stroke and it is not painful, if anyone said it is painful then it is totally a myth. If you consult good therapist then it will very helpful to recover from a stroke because he/she examines and evaluating your condition and after that gives you solution how to fight against stroke, suggest you best exercise for your body, gives you some activities which will help you to strengthen your muscles and body. This all are helpful in stroke attack and many studies have found physical therapy can help improve mobility, balance, and muscle strength.\nThank you!!!"}
{"_id": "9c5a0e5f", "question": "If you were recovering from a stroke, and in a rehabilitation facility, what would you want people to do for you?", "answers": "My husband brought me good decaffeinated coffee drinks once I was permitted normal liquids. Hospital coffee is awful!\nMy siblings got takeout from my favorite Ethiopian restaurant and we had a festive meal together. It was a nice change from hospital food.\nMy brother gave me a lovely neck and shoulder rub which relieved the pain from my affected arm hanging heavily from my shoulder. My SIL gave me an acupressure massage which may have helped sensation return to the affected arm. Could be a coincidence, but sensation returned shortly afterward.\nMy husband and daughter got training in how to help me once I was almost ready to go home. My daughter then cleared throw rugs and other trip hazards and cleared the path from my bed to the toilet. She also got non-slip mats for the bathroom and a tub-bench to help me with showering. My husband had a rail installed on the stairs and a bar beside the toilet. All these were really helpful and much appreciated.\nRehab without walls\nwas terrific after I got out of acute care rehab. They come to the home and helped me integrate back into my neighborhood. The PT & OT each came to the gym with me to help me set up a workout program that would be safe and helpful to my continuing recovery. We took BART together and they helped me figure out how to get on the escalator, how to step onto the train from the platform, etc. Little things I’d never thought about were scary! The escalator seemed to be running at super-speed."}
{"_id": "c80218fd", "question": "What useful advice can you offer someone who has a loved one recovering from a severe left brain stroke?", "answers": "First of all, I’m so sorry that they’re stuck dealing with such an unfortunate event!\nFor me, my third and final stroke, my only left-brained stroke, was the nail in my coffin. I managed to bork the OTHER side of my basal ganglia, which seems to have made me permanently exhausted. =( None of the ADD medication I took subsequent to my second stroke wakes me up anymore. It is a seemingly small, intractable, enormous problem. It sucks. I’m over it. I’m probably stuck with it for life.\nBut, in addition to my fatigue (and my increased sensitivity to sunlight and noise, my increasingly tiny handwriting, and my increasingly worse aphasia), I became depressed after my third stroke. I don’t know whether it was because people with left-brain strokes routinely become depressed or whether, after six months of dealing with this sh!t after the second stroke I was just over it, and I will never know, but man … depression sucks. I would pay good money to never, ever feel that way again. Do you remember the effect of the dementors in Harry Potter? It’s like they flew into my house and sucked out all the heat, all the love, and all the things that make life worth living. (Of course, you could also argue that’s exactly what the strokes did. You can see my confusion as to what caused the depression!)\nTwo things helped me deal with my depression: first of all, my depression led me to try Wellbutrin, which, thanks be to God!, woke me up. Not quite as spectacularly as Adderall, but it also doesn’t make me feel high all the time ;) (Which is a good thing. I feel normal on Wellbutrin.) Second of all, my husband was very up-front about it all; there was no hushed whispering about his “nutty wife”, no hesitancy to get me on medication, no reluctance to find me a counselor. I love that about him! You can certainly do that for your loved one: you can be the strong advocate for help, if they’re willing to take it.\nUnfortunately, if you’ve seen one stroke, you’ve seen one stroke — they’re so different that without more information I really can’t say, “You need a top-notch physical therapist”, “You need to go to Timbuktu to see a shaman”, or “You need to feed her lots of chocolate” — though the last one never hurts ;)\nBest of luck to you and your loved one!"}
{"_id": "8933ca45", "question": "What might cause a woman of 51 to suffer a stroke the same day as a tooth extraction? She had her first stroke 7 years ago but recovered well.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "00f0519c", "question": "How do I help a stroke victim recover?", "answers": "Take to them like you did prior to the stroke don’t , treat them the same , offer your help but don’t be pushy and don’t talk about it unless they bring it up they’re feeling like a little embarrassed because of there speech or what not so make them laugh it’s great for the muscles and their heat to feel the love from you"}
{"_id": "634e6e77", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": "Let go everything and simply meditate for a while now, dear. That's what you need to do at first. I suggest that you practice the guided meditations for beginners by Sri Sri in YouTube.\nWill you listen if I tell you one thing,dear? Let's not think about how long we will live. Let's not even bother about that. It's your quality of life that matters, not the quantity. Isn’t it?\nLet's be in the present,without thinking too much about the past and future. Let's start to focus on each day at a time. Have you been happy today? Very good if you have been happy. If you have not been happy today, be happy now dear. :) The day is still far from over. :)\nThere are so many things that you can do to be happy. Listen to some music or play musical instruments,read a good book that uplifts you or write something. Chant mantras like Om namah Shivaya for a few minutes,do pranayama,Sudarshan kriya and meditate for a while. All these can make you so happy! You have to do these to experience that.\nLet's count how many happy moments we have had today. The more the happy moments,the better the day has been for us. It's the measure of the quality of life-how many happy moments we have had.\nLet every day of ours make us satisfied-that we have utilized the day fully. How to have that satisfaction? Engage in some selfless service daily(at least an hour daily). Then you can have that satisfaction. At the end of the day, when you retire for the night(go to sleep),you can be satisfied that I have utilized my day fully-I did what I should have done. Along with selfless service,we need to meditate for a few minutes everyday.\nI suggest that you attend any one of the following programs of the Art of Living:\nOnline meditation and breath workshop(Happiness program)\nOnline Sahaj samadhi dhyana yoga\nYES! +\nYou must attend any one of these as soon as possible."}
{"_id": "9444f8cd", "question": "How expensive is it to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "First of all, I suspect that nobody has recovered fully from a stroke. Personally, I’ve done pretty well — to the point that doctors have seen me, done a couple cursory examinations, and prounounced me “all better”. That’s when I pronounce them to be idiots ;)\nI suspect it’s really expensive.\nI probably received a couple hundred thousand dollars of therapy, a hundred thousand in hospital stays, an extra 50k of hospital visits when I was pregnant because it’s thought that pregnancy hormones may have contributed to my strokes — and that’s not even considering the lost income or the insane charge I’ve racked up with Lyft because I can no longer drive.\nHowever, all this pales in comparison to … well, to losing myself. I grieved for myself for a long time. I didn’t do it publicly, but privately? You betcha! I prayed that God would just release me from this body with a broken brain. That I wouldn’t have to live another day terrified that a truck would drive by me as I walked the dogs around the block because the noise made me freak out. That the sun would just go behind a cloud, because having it shine in my face HURT my poor eyes. That I could wake up the person I used to be; be there for my husband like I used to be; become a mom like I’d wanted to; etc."}
{"_id": "5c7e0057", "question": "What's the best therapy techniques to recover from a hemorrhagic stroke?", "answers": "Fired your therapists after a six months post-stroke. At this time, you still can’t ‘wake up’ your affected arm and hand. Still, you need a RockTape binds up your subluxation shoulder. Walk a little around your neighborhood or go to the mall. My West Asheville neighborhood has a bunch of hills. Go for climbing stairs. Now, relax. Drive a car. Hike a hill. Do exercise with your arm and lie on your bed. Do yoga! I choose aikido, martial art of Japan. Do horseback riding (I love it so much! The rush catapult me to orgasmic runner high). I tremble for tango. I do it every Tuesday at night. I and my AlonTree Team make neulogical equipment for me and for YOU! Oh. Right. In December of ‘08, I had a catastrophic massive stroke at the age of 40. A brain surgeon said to my parents, “Your son has become a vegetable and he is going die.” Wow. I hope this is paradise because I have fun, fun, and FUN! going to do my exercise. www.alontree.com"}
{"_id": "87ed0c75", "question": "How long does it take to get over a heat stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "123cde54", "question": "How do you recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "cf01b49f", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a lacunar stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7a0558ef", "question": "Can a person have both kinds of strokes, hemorrhagic and ischemic strokes within 30 days, and can he recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4aadb4a2", "question": "Is it possible to completely recover from the treatment of a brain aneurysm/AVM/stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "471ce913", "question": "Has anyone had a cerebellar stroke and what did they do to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "89e2370c", "question": "How can I quickly recover from cognitive impairment after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c9edd285", "question": "Is it a miracle for an acute stroke victim to recover with little to no damage?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c75e239a", "question": "How long does a cat take to recover from fever due to heat stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "66dc902a", "question": "Is it possible for a person who has had a massive stroke, is breathing on their own, but has been in a coma for two months, to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4ef0edba", "question": "I had a stroke and now I'm recovered. Can I become an IAS officer?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2ca99e0f", "question": "Can a person recover from a stroke with no adverse effects?", "answers": "Yes, but it is unusual. Most of us suffer from slight paralysis of left or right side, walking may be affected, swallowing may be hard, balance may be off and short-term memory and speech affected. I still suffer these effects, walk with a stick and have numbness of my right hand four years after my three strokes. Physiotherapy can be very valuable. It depends on the severity of the stroke and whether is is just a blockage or if it bleeds into your brain. Those suffering a TIA usually recovered completely."}
{"_id": "81d0ffe3", "question": "Does CBD (Cannabidiol) help stroke victims recover? My mom has suffered from a stroke and has been very anxious at night. I am wondering if Cannabidiol might her calm down.", "answers": "CBD is actually excellent at treating anxiety. Marijuana can actually induce anxiety in some people, but CBD is non-psychoactive so you get all the natural healing properties without the high. The body’s endocannabinoid system\nplays a big role in the regulation of stress by gating and constraining anxiety responses within the body. CBD also doesn’t come with the side effects that other anti-anxiety medications like Xanax or Valium have.\nSorry to hear about your mom. Hope you find healing. <3"}
{"_id": "d7dd77ef", "question": "Is it possible to recover from a stroke after 7 years?", "answers": "Is it possible to recover from a stroke after 7 years. Sadly no. The hemiparesis is what it is. Muscle shortening intervention , tendon releases, losing weight and staying active will help. Now your Blood Pressure is probably controlled and you know you have Cardio-vascular disease. You have stopped smoking.\nAll these things will contribute to helping you enjoy life and be happy in the knowledge that the stroke did not kill you (or your loved one) ."}
{"_id": "9ee554ce", "question": "Can a hyperbaric chamber help stroke patients recover faster than blood thinners?", "answers": "Typically blood thinners are not for stroke recovery…. On the other hand… read on.\nHyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT) has been shown to help prevent and treat stroke through a number of different mechanisms. HBOT can be used to precondition the brain by producing more circulatory pathways to potentially decrease the chance of stroke.\nAlso, this has been shown to benefit post-stroke patients, as compromised blood flow to the affected area of the brain and its functionality are recoverable by introducing increased levels of oxygen. Studies have demonstrated the benefits of HBOT for stroke with the following:\nStroke Prevention\n• Stimulates the Creation of New Blood Vessels\n• Decreases Oxidative Stress in the Brain\n• Supports the Promotion of Optimal Blood Flow\n• Preconditions the Brain to Enable Neuroprotective Properties\nStroke Recovery\n• Supports Overall Recovery\n• Reduces Paralysis\n• Increases Brain Tissue Recovery\n• Promotes the Creation of New Brain Cells\n• Alleviates Spasticity\n• Improves Vision and Speech\n• Accelerates Gross/Fine Motor Skills Recovery\n• Stimulates the Creation of Blood Vessels to Reclaim Damaged Brain Tissue\n• Augments the Creation of New Brain Connections\nThe most important criteria being, for stroke survivors, Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy reactivates the idling neurons, stimulates growth of new blood vessels, prevents cell death, and improves neurological function."}
{"_id": "377625e5", "question": "Can a person have both kinds of strokes, hemorrhagic and ischemic strokes within 30 days, and can he recover?", "answers": "It is unfortunately quite possible. It is usually the result of therapeutics going a little too far with the result that a clot is over-treated and now becomes the blood “becoming too thin” or that the thinned blood is treated to a point where clots form. A patient that has both kind of strokes can recover but his/ her chances of permanent problems are unfortunately not that great."}
{"_id": "d66e789b", "question": "What medical help can rich people get to help them recover from a stroke?", "answers": "Basically physical therapy where you make the patient use the affected limbs while not allowing them to use the good ones.\nBut really an ounce of prevention is worth a pound of cure; going on the MIND diet, losing weight, exercising including cardio ( i run 20 miles and walk 20 miles a week) and weight training and using medication to control any risk factors is a better way to go than dealing with a stroke."}
{"_id": "1e8f86aa", "question": "Yesterday my grandma had a stroke, she hadn’t received help for 12 hours and is now paralyzed on the entire left side of her body. Does anybody know the odds of her recovering or ways to improve her recovery?", "answers": "They used to say if a person comes to the hospital within 3 hours of a stroke ,Brain damage can be prevented.But the new study suggests that the traditional three-hour time window is too short. By combining data from multiple clinical trials, Maarten Lansberg, MD, PhD, assistant professor of neurology and neurological sciences at Stanford, and colleagues from Belgium and Germany showed that treatment can benefit patients up to 4.5 hours after they experience their first symptom. Their findings were published online May 21 in the journal Stroke.\nEvery year, more than 750,000 Americans experience a stroke, or brain attack, due to a sudden drop in blood flow to the brain. Most strokes are ischemic, meaning they're caused by a blocked artery. For these strokes, a medication called tissue plasminogen activator, or tPA, can open blocked blood vessels and help restore blood flow to the brain.\nIdeally one should go to a hospital where they can go through the groin vein and remove the blood clot in the brain.\nSigns of stroke\nFace: Smile and see if one side of the face droops.\nArms: Raise both arms. Does one arm drop down?\nSpeech: Say a short phrase and check for slurred or strange speech.\nTime: If the answer to any of these is yes, call 911 right away and write down the time when symptoms started.\nWarning Signs\nSometimes a stroke happens gradually, but you’re likely to have one or more sudden symptoms like these:\nNumbness or weakness in your face, arm, or leg, especially on one side\nConfusion or trouble understanding other people\nDifficulty speaking\nTrouble seeing with one or both eyes\nProblems walking or staying balanced or coordinated\nDizziness\nA severe headache that comes on for no reason\nIf you have these symptoms, call 911 even if you’re not sure you’re having a stroke.\n3 Types of Strokes\nIschemic Strokes (Clots)\nIschemic strokes\noccur as a result of an obstruction within a blood vessel supplying blood to the brain. The underlying condition for this type of obstruction is the development of fatty deposits lining the vessel walls. This condition is called atherosclerosis. These fatty deposits can cause two types of obstruction:\nCerebral thrombosis refers to a thrombus (blood clot) that develops at the clogged part of the vessel.\nCerebral embolism refers generally to a blood clot that forms at another location in the circulatory system, usually the heart and large arteries of the upper chest and neck. A portion of the blood clot breaks loose enters the bloodstream and travels through the brain’s blood vessels until it reaches vessels too small to let it pass. A second important cause of embolism is an irregular heartbeat, known as atrial fibrillation. It creates conditions where clots can form in the heart, dislodge and travel to the brain.\nHemorrhagic Strokes (Bleeds)\nHemorrhagic\nstroke\naccounts for about 13 percent of stroke cases. It results from a weakened vessel that ruptures and bleeds into the surrounding brain. The blood accumulates and compresses the surrounding brain tissue. The two types of hemorrhagic strokes are intracerebral (within the brain) hemorrhage or subarachnoid hemorrhage. Hemorrhagic stroke occurs when a weakened blood vessel ruptures. Two types of weakened blood vessels usually cause hemorrhagic stroke. An aneurysm is a ballooning of a weakened region of a blood vessel. If left untreated, the aneurysm continues to weaken until it ruptures and bleeds into the brain. An arteriovenous malformation (AVM) is a cluster of abnormally formed blood vessels. Any one of these vessels can rupture, also causing bleeding into the brain.\nTransient Ischemic Attack (TIA)\nTIAs are often labeled mini-strokes\nbecause they can be relatively benign in terms of immediate consequences. But the term “warning stroke” is more appropriate for these temporary episodes, because they can indicate the likelihood of a coming stroke. A TIA is a temporary blockage of blood flow to the brain. The blockage is short-term or temporary during a TIA or warning stroke. The clot may dissolve on it its own or get dislodged so that it stops causing the symptoms. Temporary symptoms may occur. A third of U.S. adults have had symptoms consistent with a TIA. The symptoms are similar to an ischemic stroke, but TIA symptoms usually last less than five minutes with an average of about a minute. When a TIA is over, that particular blockage usually causes no permanent injury to the brain.\nSorry about your grandma.She will have to go through physical therapy and will be able to walk ."}
{"_id": "a841326f", "question": "How long do stroke patients take to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "54bc8fe5", "question": "Will Citalopram help my mental state in recovering a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "6ac3a3d4", "question": "What percentage can recover from a brain stem stroke?", "answers": "That is one of the types of stroke with lower chance of survival and less chance of good recovery in those who do survive.\nThe person’s doctor is the one to ask, but they are likely to be cautious. When I had a hemorrhagic stroke, my husband was told “IF I survived the first night in ICU, I should be alright.” I survived, but I have deficits that will remain the rest of my life."}
{"_id": "cff9b633", "question": "Can movement, feeling etc be recovered a years or longer after a stroke?", "answers": "So I had a hemorrhagic stroke after an arterial dissection 10 years ago. Part of the ongoing issue that I’ve been having involves temperature…my left side no longer interprets temperature correctly, if something is too hot or too cold, it just hurts. So this made swimming impossible…I’d put a foot in, it would just hurt, I’d pull it out. Even in the shower, I still have to put my right side in first, then slowly bring the left in.\nAnyway, two years ago my wife and I went on a cruise to Bermuda. I tried going in a swimming pool in preparation, and had absolutely no pain. It was amazing! I stayed in for an hour, not wanting to break the spell, I really misses swimming. On the boat, I tried a hot tub, again, no problems. Finally, I attempted to swim in the ocean in Bermuda, and was absolutely fine.\nSo I did recover something. I tried every year to go swimming, and was never able to do so, but finally something healed enough to allow me to do it again. It can be done! They say something like 95% of the healing takes place in the first year, but the brain works in mysterious ways, always looking for opportunities to heal."}
{"_id": "ce28fd79", "question": "Should I tell my pregnant sister that our father had a stroke and he is in the hospital and he may die or should I wait maybe he recovers? Could an emotional shock have an effect on the baby?", "answers": "I’ll tell you what will be more likely to have an affect on the baby, if you don’t tell her her father is gravely ill and he dies without her getting chance to say goodbye. Not only will the mother go through a period of anger and hatred (at you) she will be depressed she missed her opportunity to spend time with (affecting the child) and the child will probably never know its aunt/uncle (you) because she will never forgive you or let you be a part of their lives"}
{"_id": "e83ff259", "question": "How serious is aortic regurgitation in a man who recently had a stroke, but has recovered, has a pacemaker from severe bradycardia, and is 70 years old?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "fd3a7859", "question": "What are some essential supplements you need to take to recover from a stroke?", "answers": "I’m sorry to hear that you or a loved one has had a stroke, but happy s/he is recovering.\nAs soon as he or she can swallow safely, I would start with nourishing vegetable soups. You can puree them if chewing is an issue. Use a variety of vegetables. Simmer them in a base of homemade chicken bone stock. Don’t add salt. Use fresh garlic, onions, leeks and spices to amp up the flavor, then add fresh herbs and a squeeze of fresh lemon to each serving. Herbs have many healing properties and acid enhances flavors.\nI eat lots of wild-caught fish, especially Alaskan Salmon and black cod. They are both low in mercury and high in Omega-3 fatty acids — and they are delicious! Sardines and herring are other good choices.\nI get a box of in-season veggies delivered weekly from a nearby farm. Now, it contains a lot of greens and winter squash. Both are highly nutritious, but I supplement with things that catch my eye in the market. Tokyo turnips, for instance. Both the greens and the white bulbs are very nutritious and not nearly as strong as the purple top turnips.\nCheck with his/her doctor for and deficiencies and discuss how to address them.\nI was off-the-charts low in Vitamin D. In the hospital, they also gave me Potassium for a few days and Magnesium for a few days. To fix it, I supplemented with a lot of Vitamin D for six weeks until my levels returned to the normal range, and I eat foods rich in Potassium and Magnesium every day.\nDon’t fall for the scam-of-the-week supplements. Simply eat well, take meds as directed and exercise as much as he or she is able. Slow and steady wins the race."}
{"_id": "17345e37", "question": "How does music help stroke patients recover?", "answers": "From https://www.neurologytimes.com/stroke/music-stroke-recovery\nMechanisms of stroke recovery with music therapy\nAs with most rehabilitative techniques, challenging and using the injured brain can improve abilities. Exactly how and why this happens on a cellular level remains unclear. There are several leading theories regarding the mechanism by which music therapy improves patient abilities in stroke recovery.\nMusic plays a large role in mood for many people. Musical pieces can elicit pleasant or unpleasant emotions that are rooted in life memories. The response of mood to music may be conscious or subconscious. Music that evokes memories of pleasant interpersonal connections or achievements may elevate the mood of some stroke survivors. Positive mood has been shown to play a significant role in stroke recovery.\nAdditionally, rehabilitative techniques are believed to augment neuroplasticity. Yet why some methods seem to have this effect is not clear. And, yet another theory is that enhanced connectivity between regions of the brain can allow stroke survivors to regain skills that were lost. There are some overlaps between this idea and that of theories surrounding neuroplasticity, but there are also some aspects of the two concepts that are independent.\nThus far, research on music therapy in stroke recovery is favorable. Given the relatively low cost of music therapy and the lack of treatment for brain injury incurred by stroke, it is an interesting option for recovering stroke patients."}
{"_id": "3c3d9deb", "question": "Have you had a stroke? Did you manage to recover?", "answers": "Well I guess I did. I was in the hospital for something else, so the Dr wanted a cat scan. When I was feeling better the Dr came to talk to me and he told me that the cat scan showed that I had 3 Tia's. That means I had 3 mini strokes. He ask me if I can remember any problems. So he referred me to a neurologist. The neurologist wanted to send me for more tests. One ofthemisa MRI. Well that didn't go well cuz I am extremely costraphobic. So I never took that test. I also never went back to see him. He was very rude to me and a complete butt hole! I haven't had any symptoms and it's been over a year. I am counting my many blessings that it does not rear it's ugly face."}
{"_id": "ef0e76a6", "question": "Can you recover from a thalamic stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e6ff5b8e", "question": "Has Surekha Sikri recovered from a brain stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "61bfb7af", "question": "How did your loved one recover from their stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "50ba65d8", "question": "What is the simplest and most effective medication or practice to prescribe for someone recovering from stroke (partial paralysis) for quick healing?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9dd7584a", "question": "Can a brain fully recover from a stroke that significantly damaged the left hemisphere?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7cf17c19", "question": "Can you recover from a pons stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "27f044c0", "question": "Can my 71-year-old husband recover from his stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f71b5d53", "question": "Do stroke patients recover better at home?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e130420f", "question": "What are some effective ways to improve aphasia in people recovering from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d848d2a5", "question": "Is there an easier faster affordable way to recover from stroke disability than physiotherapy? It’s been 6 years of physiotherapy and I’m still in this God awful wheelchair with left side paralysis. Has anyone successfully done it?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "802a6480", "question": "Is it possible for an elderly person, who also has stage 4 cancer, to recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f5d35e73", "question": "Can \"Brain gym\" help people recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1cecc7be", "question": "How long does it take for an elderly person to recover from severe dehydration in particular slurred speech and confusion? CT scan shows no sign of stroke.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "8c130c78", "question": "Can a 90-year-old recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7bc6bc98", "question": "Can you recover from a basal ganglia stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5b2956e7", "question": "What is the best remedy for a 71 year old man to recover from a mild stroke? He cannot walk on his own without support and his vitals has been fairly good.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "b852b6e4", "question": "Of the people who recover from COVID-19, how many die months later from strokes and heart attacks?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "363affd3", "question": "Can a dog recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f6c04095", "question": "How do I stop missing my mom? I’m almost 16 and it’s been almost two years without my mom. She had a stroke and suffers paralysis and a leg amputation. She can’t take care of herself and chooses drugs over trying to get better and recover.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2fe8ddb7", "question": "When a stroke or brain damage causes a person to have to re-learn language, how does the brain typically adapt? Do the damaged parts recover or do other parts of the brain take over, and how does this affect the relearning process?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2a6a76ef", "question": "Can you recover brain damage after a heat stroke, if yes, how?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5f6336f2", "question": "How can I help my fifty-year-old sister recover from a hemorrhagic stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e3638592", "question": "How do I tell my dad that his wife tried to kill him and stole his money while he was recovering from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5d0a5f3b", "question": "Can an 85-year-old recover from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "5332804d", "question": "Can a person recover when the largest part of the brain is affected by a stroke?", "answers": "Our brain is incredibly resilient to diseases like strokes given proper time and care.\nThe brain has got a property of plasticity. This means that in case the brain has sustained an injury like a stroke, there is functional re-organization of circuits in brain that can take place. Here, the parts adjacent to damaged areas starts reorganizing themselves and take over the functions of the damaged area. This again is dependent on the quality of rehabilitation initiated after stroke. The rehabilitation helps the brain to learn how to perform a function that was lost due to stroke like lifting up an arm or to speak. Thus the rehabilitative strategies like physiotherapy and speech therapy adopted helps the brain to regain it's lost function and recover from stroke to a large extend.\nHowever, if a large part of brain is affected, the chance of recovery comes down because the normal areas that must learn the functions of the damaged parts are meager.\nRecovery from a major stroke that has involved a large area of brain then depends upon factors like age of the patient, stroke severity, the quantum of neurologic deficits, the level of sensorium, co-morbidities, intercurrent complications like aspiration pneumonia and urinary infection, development of bed sores, the extend to which nursing care and rehabilitative measures are provided etc...\nAs already mentioned in the outset, our brain is quite neuro-plastic & resilient and recovery after a stroke even if large area of brain is affected it not beyond reach."}
{"_id": "7533903c", "question": "Has Timothy Omundson recovered from his stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "27af5246", "question": "Does post-hospital treatment help stroke patients recover faster?", "answers": "Definitely! Hospitalization is needed to stabilize stroke survivors, but after they’ve stabilized medically, they need various therapies to regain functions that were lost or damaged by the stroke.\nPhysical and occupational therapies may help them learn to walk and to use the affected arm. Speech therapy can help them with cognitive deficits as well as regaining speech. Psychological therapy can help them learn to adjust to their limitations.\nA good neuro-rehab team can assess the damage and put together a plan of action. Warehousing stroke survivors in nursing homes almost guarantees that they will be invalids for the rest of their lives."}
{"_id": "4a9b9908", "question": "I had a stroke in October, still nowhere near recovered. If you had a stroke or knew someone who did, how long did it take them to get back to where they were before the stroke?", "answers": "It can be years; it can be never.\nYou might want to read My Stroke of Insight, by Jill Bolte Taylor. If you cannot yet read for long periods of time, try listening to the book on audio or having someone read it to you.\nJill actually had an AVM blow-out, rather than a stroke, per se. For most of what she has to say, the difference is not important."}
{"_id": "8e77b33f", "question": "What are some good ways to encourage the regeneration of neurons in the brain when recovering from a stroke?", "answers": "Cognitive exercises\nPhysical therapy - multimodal\nSinging (yes, singing)\nFish oil\nB-complex vitamins\nVitamin B-12\nVitamin D\nCoenzyme Q-10\nProbiotics"}
{"_id": "2c1f07c5", "question": "How can I recover my vocabulary after a stroke?", "answers": "Try to start reading newspaper regularly by which you will get all the words which are used in daily writing. You can buy word power made easy by norman lewis which is giant of vocabulary\nYou can follow this link to learn vocabulary on regular basis My Vocabulary Collection"}
{"_id": "415a9d30", "question": "What is the probability of a 40+ year old woman surviving and recovering a stroke? She’s in an induced coma with minimal brain activity.", "answers": "Many years ago, the course of strokes was less predictable because they did not have as good of imaging techniques as we have today. Today, when the doctors see a devastating stroke, they are upfront with the family because they do not want to present them with false hope.\nThese statements are all true:\n· People in a vegetative state due to stroke, loss of oxygen to the brain (anoxia) or some types of severe medical illness may not recover as well as those with traumatic brain injury.\n· By reducing the activity in the brain and slowing its metabolism, an induced coma can help protect the neural (nerve tissue) by reducing the work of brain cells.\n· The slowing of brain function is necessary to prevent damage that can be done by a lack of blood flow.\n· When patients are in a medically induced coma, the brain is quiet for up to several seconds at a time, punctuated by short bursts of activity. This pattern, known as burst suppression, allows the brain to conserve vital energy during times of trauma.\n· Stroke severity and patient age are the two most important factors in predicting one’s chances of survival after a stroke.\n\"A wide variety of factors influence stroke prognosis, including age, stroke severity, stroke mechanism, infarct location, comorbid conditions, clinical findings, and related complications. In addition, interventions such as thrombolysis, stroke unit care, and rehabilitation can play a major role in the outcome of ischemic stroke.\"\n(see article, Ischemic stroke prognosis in adults by Matthew A Edwardson, MD\n).\nSo, let's take this one, one at a time. At age 40, she is younger than most, and that can be good. You do not say if this was a minimal or a massive stroke but I am assuming since they put her into a medically induced coma, it was pretty significant, so that is bad. Stroke outcomes are better if the person gets diagnosed quickly and get medication in them known as clot busters.\nThere are two types of stroke; one where a blood clot lodges and blocks off blood flow, which is called an ischemic stroke, and one where they had a bleed, called a hemorrhagic stroke. You did not mention which type it was, but as you will see from the next statement, stroke statistics are pretty grim.\n\"Of the surviving patients, 60 percent who suffered an ischemic stroke and 38 percent with intracerebral hemorrhage survived one year, compared to 31 percent and 24 percent, respectively, after five years. At the end of the [five year] study, 29 percent of the stroke patients were still alive.\"\n(see article, Stroke Survival Statistics: 9 Sobering Facts We Should All Be Aware Of, Saebo,\nMonday, June 11th, 2018).\nThe brain is complex and tricky. In all of the areas of medicine I worked in, neuro-trauma was both the most devastating AND the most miraculous. It also seems to be an area where doctors still say, \"We just don't know\" more than any other area.\nMy advice to you, if you are visiting with her, is to touch her gently and talk to her quietly if the medical staff approves. Take things one day at a time. Pray, and hope for the best, but . . ., prepare for the worst."}
{"_id": "a112fb87", "question": "Can someone fully recover from a mild stroke? Does age matter?", "answers": "Yes.\nI know lots of people who have had strokes. The new clot busting medications are great. Treatment of stroke patients has changed so much in the last couple of decades with new medications.\nSome people have small strokes- called a TIA- my understanding is a TIA is a tiny blood clot that partially blocked a vein somewhere , then passed on through. TIA’s have no lasting effect on a person. TIA is transeschemic attack. Probably spelled that wrong- I’m lazy right now.\nOther patients have blood clots that paralyze them temporarily until we bust up the clot. Then slowly the paralysis goes away & function returns over time.\nThe bigger the blood clot the bigger physical effects, of the clot goes to the brain, the lungs- not good.\nYounger people rehabilitate faster than old folks."}
{"_id": "276a1dc4", "question": "I’m 43 and I was a stroke when I was 36. My half body can move slowly and can walk. How long can I recover my left arm and leg back to normal?", "answers": "Part of your brain was irreversibly damaged by the stroke but there is a lot of brain left and even the adult brain exhibits “plasticity” meaning it can, to an extent, reconfigure itself to allow other parts to take over the function of the damaged region. This is like the process of learning and depends on repeated attempts to undertake tasks, plus encouragement with positive feedback, over a period of years. It’s never too late to make progress but it’s impossible to predict how much function can be restored."}
{"_id": "9667bd95", "question": "Has anyone ever recovered their vision after an eye stroke (retinal vein occlusion)?", "answers": "Yes…to varying degrees. Much more so than a Retinal Artery Occlusion. Here’s an analogy I use: if you were growing crops in a desert, and you cut off the water supply, the plants would die, and be dead. That’s an RAO. If you flooded the plants, for way too long, some of them would die, some would come back but not thrive, and some would grow back just fine. That’s more like an RVO.\nThe retina just gets clogged up with too much, “stuff”, and has to dry it all out. So, really, it ends up being how long it was flooded, if and when it was treated, or how long has it been in the process of “drying up”. A bunch of unknowns, but, I’ve seen patients come back pretty well, even after a year.\nThen the question remains, how are you treating the underlying cause of it?"}
{"_id": "06d02db7", "question": "Can someone recover from a stroke if their voice has been changed since then?", "answers": "Partial recovery is very usual, but total recovery less so.\nPatients with strokes should never abandon hope of continuing, if limited, recovery. They should not, however, be unrealistic in their expectations and go on 'hoping against hope', because most of their recovery occurs relatively early. However, there are always exceptions."}
{"_id": "9642104c", "question": "How do I get my daughter to give me back my deceased mother's wedding ring that I gave her to hold for me while I was in the hospital recovering from 2 strokes?", "answers": "Just ask her. But what do you intend to do with it. Gifts given while alive are more important. If you really need it back. Tell her that you really need it back. Why the hesitation. Did you imply that you were giving it to her. Or did you give it to her and now you changed your mind. It's important but your relationship with your daughter is more important.\nYour next decision is very important. What is more important to you. Or is this just a simple discussion, over a meal, thanking her for taking care of the ring."}
{"_id": "ab12ba41", "question": "How admissible are statements made by a heavily sedated hospital patient recovering from a massive stroke?", "answers": "According to Indian law at least, if the statement was a dying declaration or deposition, it would hold immense ground, irrespective of whether sedatives had been administered to the patient or not, more so if it was the latter. In all other cases, the defendant could easily question the mental capacity of the patient at the time of the statement, the dilemma being resolved by a certificate given by an attending medical officer testifying whether the patient was mentally fit to give any statement at the given time. Generally, such a certificate is a mandatory requirement before recording a statement."}
{"_id": "3eb38573", "question": "What are the chances of recovering if a female suffers from a lacunar stroke at the age of 60?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1d0d44f8", "question": "How do I recover my left side body numbness as I was diagnosed due to a mild stroke?", "answers": "Go for a fortnight-long therapy, including massage and medicines, at the Kottakal Arya Vaidya Sala hospitals in Kerala."}
{"_id": "d0264e65", "question": "If strokes occur on both sides of the brain, how much time does a person need to recover fully?", "answers": "It depends on the extent the brain has suffered and the kinds of problems it has left you with. Some people have trouble walking, speaking or serve forms of these. this can take a long time but takes about 6 months with therapy to improve considerably."}
{"_id": "4e8e6585", "question": "Did Woodrow Wilson recover from his stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1031597b", "question": "Can a stroke patient recover after 1 year or some time?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "72647c2e", "question": "What type of music therapy can help my mother to recover from stroke and spasticity? Are there any on YouTube?", "answers": "Is it that her spasticity only on right upper and lower limbs, in that case she might also have some kind of speech abnormalities called aphasia due to stroke on the left frontal cortex.\nSuch patients could improve their speech defects by trying to sing the songs they are already accustomed to. So you need to play any of those songs and urge your mom to rehearse concordantly.\n(I don't know if I could make you understand what I mean to say)"}
{"_id": "a07ee3a9", "question": "How does a person recover speech after a left hemisphere stroke?", "answers": "I had 2 left hemisphere strokes. You have to practice speech every day for as long as you can. Read aloud. It may take all year to get it back.\nI decided to try to learn something new at the same time. I’ve read many non-fiction books aloud, which also helps with memory loss.\n3 years later, I’m still working on it."}
{"_id": "db3ad6cd", "question": "For stroke survivors that recovered fully in the short term, did the symptoms return when you got older?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4f137ff2", "question": "What are the methods to recover lost muscle function in paralysis (hemiplegia) caused by ishemic stroke?", "answers": "What are the methods to recover lost muscle function in paralysis caused by ischemic stroke?\nI had an ischemic stroke almost 3 years ago now. I,too, suffered from hemiplegia, on the left side. I don’t consider myself fully recovered yet, since I still can’t run properly, and still have some weakness in my left foot. But otherwise, everyone tells me there is no noticeable indication I ever had a stroke nor was hemiplegic, so I guess as far as ordinary daily living goes, I’verecovered.\nMethods? Essentially, physical therapy: exercises and electric stimulation. The therapist used this little device the name of which escapes me now, sorry. The device essentially sent electric current to stimulate the muscles during a particular task. So, for example, it was attached to my bicep, and while I was trying to lift my arm, the device helped with the muscle contraction. Same with tricep exercises, and foot exercises. It took a little bit of knowledge of anatomy to knowwhere to attach the device though. Then lots of exercise and practice. Then I just progressed to more difficult tasks.\nBUt the whole thing wasn’t easy. It required concentration, focus, and lots and lots of patience. I was doing PT almost everyday, an hour a day. I think it took me about a year before I had the confidence to try getting around by myself, like going back to school for my PhD, driving the car, swimming by myself without any safety device like floaters, and riding my bike.\nSo I hope I answered your question . TLDR: electric stimulation and exercise. Best of luck to you or the person you’re asking for."}
{"_id": "1bd6029b", "question": "Once you format and reinstall Windows to your computer. Can you still recover the words that were typed on that computer? Can we still recover the keyboard strokes?", "answers": "If the keystrokes were written to a file then it may be possible to recover depending on when the file was deleted. If it was deleted long ago then , the sectors might have got overwritten and recovery may not be possible. Else you can use recovery softwares like RecoverMyFiles to get back the file.\nUsually on Reinstlalling Windows, the HDD gets wiped properly because there happens a formatting phase before installing happens.\nSo, i would suggest to give it a try."}
{"_id": "4138e239", "question": "Does Ceragem prove to be useful for paralytic stroke patients to recover quickly?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4771682e", "question": "I read somewhere that video games could help someone recover from a stroke. If this is true, which games were they?", "answers": "Reading this question, I have begun to feel the skepticism slowly arising inside of me. But, as it turns out, that thing is very much real. There are even TED talks about that stuff, wow. It caught me by surprise, no less.\nAs more effort and research are being devoted to video games and virtual reality for stroke recovery treatment, there may be a new solution on the horizon. Ideally, therapy is repetitive, task-specific, challenging, and exciting—video games address these needs and more through one of the brain’s natural processes called neuroplasticity, where nerve cell connections are recreated and remodeled. The brain strengthens neural networks through tasks that are repeated and habitual. These actions are naturally easier to perform due to neural pathways being well traveled. Doing or thinking about something new or in a different manner allows the brain to create new pathways or awaken old ones. Activities designed in video games help patients do just that.\nGames that help (?) with stroke recovery:\nBrain Age\nDance Dance Revolution\nWii Bowling\nFitMi"}
{"_id": "e52a83bc", "question": "What are your thoughts on the comment that \"COVID 19 is the worst disease. When they say 'recovered' they don’t tell you that it means you may need a lung transplant or you may get a massive heart attack or stroke\"?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4c73d572", "question": "What does it mean when you’ve had a heart attack and stroke at same time left side of your brain continues to swell. Then are put on a ventilator because your not breathing o own? Can you recover from this?", "answers": "So, when you have a heart attack, something happens that causes the supply of blood, which carries all the goodies like oxygen, Ions and other nutrients to the muscle tissue of the heart to be cut off enough to cause it to stop beating. When your heart stops beating this means no other parts of your body can get those same goodies in the blood that they need to do their jobs. if the other parts of your body don’t do their jobs, things start breaking down in the body that ultimately can lead to someone passing.\nWhen you have a stroke, on a very basic level it’s the same thing, part of your brain has been deprived of all the nutrients it needs to do its job, which is causing the other parts of the body to function properly. While not always the case, strokes are often caused by a blood vessel in the brain breaking and leaking blood away from the tissues of the brain. The swelling of the brain in this case seems to be due to the blood from a burst vessel pooling in the skull and not flowing where it normally should. If the swelling continues it can put more pressure on the brain and injure it further, so if the blood or possibly fluid can’t be diverted through other means, they might have to perform surgery or insert some device to take the fluid out and take pressure off the brain.\none of the major functions of the brain is to help regulate your breathing. If your brain has been injured by pressure from pooling blood or fluid or from being deprived of the nutrients it needs in the blood, then it will have trouble controlling the patients breathing well enough to keep them alive so they might have to be attached to a ventilator so that the machine can do the breathing for the patient.\nLots of people do recover from heart attacks and from strokes. The only thing to keep in mind is that brain tissue and heart tissue in general don’t heal quite as well as things like your skin, so while the patient might be able to come off the ventilator, their mind might not be the same or they might have movement or speech or other difficulties depending on what part of the brain was injured. Likewise with the heart while some of the damage from the heart attack might heal, there’s no guarantee it will all heal, and it’s likely that even if the patient is well enough to leave the hospital they might not have the same capacity for activity that requires their heart to work harder like it once did."}
{"_id": "63c0f3c8", "question": "Is there any chances of recovering of a patient if he or she had suffered from brain stroke and his or her brain cells are down?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ba1fcd68", "question": "When recovering from a stroke, what are some good exercises for survivors to improve spacticity or muscular hypertonia?", "answers": "Yoga therapy. I credit it for the major portion of my physical recovery after my stroke. Not regular yoga - but yoga therapy, it is VERY different. And done by someone certified in yoga therapy, not your local yoga teacher."}
{"_id": "01ecb1dd", "question": "Should I be worried about breaking the news of my divorce to my mother who is recovering from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e10d98fc", "question": "My eye was not fully recovered from 2 minor strokes after treatment. What should I do?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "896e017c", "question": "Do you think exercising by using the pegboard is a useful way to recover hand motion after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2798d0ee", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "ca9ee60c", "question": "I'm recovering from a stroke, but exercise is boring. Would you please inspire me?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7f5c3999", "question": "One day I came home and my cat was paralyzed from the waste down. Did she have a stroke? The vet wasn't sure, but she fully recovered.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "78b0715f", "question": "Has anyone recovered enough to restart motorcycling after surviving a brain haemorrhage stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "dee78f18", "question": "How long does it take to recover from a mild stroke? What is the recovery process?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0d798732", "question": "How does neuromodulation help patients recover after a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "aca30421", "question": "What helped you recover after stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "30627df0", "question": "How long does a female around 60 take to recover from 1 brain stroke (acute paralysis)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "98753813", "question": "Can a person aged 57 years old completely recover from a brain stroke (ischemic)?", "answers": "Thats a good question and raises the issue of aging. As we grow older, our brain loses its plasticity and therefore the ability to recover.\nYet, there is no good predictor of who will recover and not, depending on numerous factors including sex, age, ethnicity, co-morbidity factors……\nAs a very big rule of thumb, we estimate that the brain recovery will likely take place within six months, after that period the chance of recovery is close to zero.\nThus, there is a big emphasis on research to try to maximize on the brain repair and understand which mechanisms are associated with improved recovery."}
{"_id": "21c559c3", "question": "Is it possible to recover from an ischemic stroke which involve posterior part of basal ganglia, posterior part of internal capsule?", "answers": "It is possible. It depends on how much brain damage has been done\nThe scenario here is not a good one. There are many better and worse.\nA lot depends on the age. Children can survive and do quite will with a hemispherectomy. This is a very rarely done operation.\nIn short it is possible to survive such an injury"}
{"_id": "bfa1fe63", "question": "I'm a type 2 diabetic, suffer from very high blood pressure, I had a brain haemorrhage stroke in December '19 (recovering well) I'm 55 years old. What's my chances of surviving Coronavirus if I get it?", "answers": "Ok, if you practice all of the health precautions without fail, this pandemic will blow over. If you’re mindful and smart, this pandemic will pass without you ever getting infected.\nI highly recommend that you change your diet, do mild exercise, and quit using whatever substances that you’re addicted to. Remember the quote from the Terminator films: There is no fate but what we make.\nIt likely won’t be the pandemic that will kill you, but your poor overall health. I would get your affairs in order either way. I’d be surprised if you live past 60 in your current state. Sorry, but it’s the truth."}
{"_id": "9879e081", "question": "Can your mental ability or cognitive abilities change after a stroke, and if so, can they be recovered?", "answers": "Yes, unfortunately those funtions can be damaged depending on the location and severity of the blood vessel blockage, bleeding or rupture. Recovery also depends on the extent of damage occurring. Thus, recovery of function may be total, partial, or ruled out completely.\nBUT, ‘brain plasticity’ allows not only for levels of possible recovery at the damaged site — it also allows for adjacent brain areas (which are undamaged) to gradually take over the lost functions. New neural pathways can be forged, or sometimes redundant brain regions assume a greater role. Still, this may entail an arduous process of rehabilitation, but it is within possibility. Only the attending neurologist can predict an approximation on chances for recovery."}
{"_id": "26319180", "question": "My husband had a stroke in 2019. He has recovered but can no longer move his right arm and walks by dragging his right leg. His workplace forced him to quit or they would fire him- can they do this?", "answers": "If he didn’t recover enough to do the job in 2019, even with ADA consideration, then he could have opt to be fired and appeal the termination with the labour board in 2019.\nIf he was given ADA accommodations and in 2021 was using the stroke from 2019 as an excuse to be less productive he failed. If he chooses to be fired and appeal the decision, the labour board or DWD will provide a written determination which will show who was at fault. A labor lawyer licensed in your zip Code can explain next steps only if they rule in favor of your husband.\nBlaming the employer because the man had a stroke is very misguided. Blame will not solve the limitations husband has that is affecting his earning power."}
{"_id": "ea77f1a7", "question": "Will Andrew Marr ever fully recover from the consequences of his stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "90fb98f2", "question": "Would testosterone help with pain of walking? I'm recovering from a stroke, walking takes all my energy.", "answers": "Testosterone is not a pain killer. It will however make you stronger and sometimes give you more energy, especially when first starting HRT."}
{"_id": "053ebb7c", "question": "If the president has a stroke and takes some time to recover from a relatively mild injury to him, can he lead the country for a total of 4 years since he doesn't need to campaign in the second term if he wins?", "answers": "Q: If the president has a stroke and takes some time to recover from a relatively mild injury to him, can he lead the country for a total of 4 years since he doesn't need to campaign in the second term if he wins?\nIf the President has a stroke, or any health issue, that incapacitates him, he can be removed from office per the 25th amendment. It would depend on how severely he was impacted, however. Keep in mind that FDR was a cripple due to polio during his time in office, and JFK was addicted to drugs (methamphetamine).\nThe only President that comes to my mind that was unable to serve due to an illness (a severe stroke) was Woodrow Wilson. His wife, Edith, was the de facto head of the Executive branch for about a year and a half as a result. She technically doesn't qualify, but she was in a practical sense the first woman President.\nEdith Wilson - Wikipedia\nIf the President has to \"take time to recover\" from some issue, it may be enough to have him removed him from office. A short break, like when Reagan was shot, probably wouldn't be enough as the VP would step in for the duration. But after a certain point (politically determined, of course), it could trigger removal."}
{"_id": "b719021e", "question": "How do I apologize to my elderly father recovering from stroke after saying some hurtful things when I was just heated in the moment after he yelled at my kids?", "answers": "Dealing with kids and ailing parents can be very difficult, and sometimes words happen! I know we all are just trying to protect our kids.\nTell your father that you love him very much and that you understand he is going through a lot at the moment. You also realize kids can be a handful at times, so next time a situation arises, he could come to you or another adult to intercede with the kids. Tell him you are sorry and that you could have handled the situation differently because you never meant/want to hurt him."}
{"_id": "1c81dacc", "question": "As a body builder for the age of 60+, how much protein must my mom have to recover leg muscles after her stroke? What is some other advice for this?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "89475f07", "question": "Entertainer Watch: Luke Perry is hospitalized in Los Angeles after suffering a massive stroke at the age of 52, do you think he will recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "60fc8788", "question": "How can one recover immediately when he/she realizes that heat stroke is attacking?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "435210bf", "question": "My father is affected with a brain stroke on the left side of the brain. Can he recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "7cf92230", "question": "Has anyone recovered from arm paresis after a stroke and cervical spine injury?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d71b7caf", "question": "Is there anything I can give my dog to help him sleep while he's recovering from a stroke?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "65e49801", "question": "What exercises would you recommend to a patient recovering from stroke (left brain)?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "142324b5", "question": "Who is the best doctor for neuroscience in Bangalore? My mother suffered a brain stroke attack last year and she has not yet recovered from cognitive issues. Any referral to good doctors or good hospitals will be very helpful.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "61b2ffd8", "question": "What can heal the cerebral ischemic stroke? Does my grandpa still have a chance to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0295c8e2", "question": "Which is the best health insurance coverage policy in India for a 46-year-old man who had a stroke five years back (recovered completely)? Which insurance gives the best medical expenses coverage along with monthly/quarterly premium payment plans?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "73d7b910", "question": "What can I say to my boyfriend's mother for not approving our relationship because I got a stroke (2 years, recovering well, but slowly) at a young age (34)? We have been together for 1 year and we’re from a different family background.", "answers": "Your boyfriend will be the one to decide how much his mother influences him. You have no control over that.\nAs far as what do we think of her for not approving of your relationship with the guy?\nWe think she’s a putz, of course."}
{"_id": "4a2feaec", "question": "How long does it take to die from bulimia? Bulimia came into my life 4 months ago. It quickly went to throwing up once a week to it becoming my whole life. I had 2 strokes, 2 seizures, and much more. I feel close to death. Can I still recover?", "answers": "YES YOU CAN RECOVER. I’m in recovery and i have watched people recover and live amazing, full, happy lives. It’s hard to portray in words but the transformation is unbelievable. You are in a very dark place right now, I know how that feels, but there is so so so much more waiting for you. And that’s starts with recovery. Actually, you’ve already started!! Congrats you took the first step by wanting to recover and asking about it. Now you need to ask for help and find a team to help you. I recommend searching up NEDA and using their helpline to get assistance creating a recovery plan and finding affordable treatment options near you. You have your whole life ahead of you- go and LIVE IT ❤️"}
{"_id": "1ca9c44b", "question": "What is the best way, in your opinion, to recover from PTSD? Worth mentioning; had a stroke & I'm currently okay but left with terrible anxiety I never had before.", "answers": "The most PTSD that is fixed usually involves talk therapy and meds. In Iowa, where they are grappling with medicinal marijuana rules, PTSD is one thing that they are allowing medicinal marijuana for. If you are a veteran, the VA would be the place to start. If not, your local social services people can probably help you get started.\nI have lived most of my life with hereditary generalized anxiety. Several people in my family have struggled with it. There are meds now that work really good. Don’t be afraid to try some medication to help. Your doctor or therapist can recommend something for you. Good luck!!"}
{"_id": "4bb6fe8c", "question": "How has been your experience of dealing with a family member with multiple stroke induced vascular dementia who ultimately recovered from the situation?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0db05f4e", "question": "My husband is 73 his stroke was caused by endocarditis. Will he fully recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4a23be41", "question": "How long does a person live after recovering from a hemorrhagic stroke? Do they have shorter lives? What do the statistics say?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "c64c6ebf", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit.", "answers": "Your lifespan will reduce if you dont goto doctor. Stroke is the reduction of blood supply to brain. How can accident cause internal problems is questionable. What kind of accident and without any details shows some vagueness. How will you know for sure you had a stroke. If you know you had a stroke, wont you be knowledgeable enough to know this as well?? How can any normal person differentiate cleanly between strokes, heart attacks (myocardial infarction), seizures (epilepsy), brain hemorrhage? I know these tech terms only through online. Im nothing even close to a doctor."}
{"_id": "1e5050a8", "question": "Can a person have both kinds of strokes, hemorrhagic and ischemic strokes within 30 days, and can he recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9e316006", "question": "What should a person who's had a stroke due to high blood pressure eat to recover her health? She still has a SYS of190- 210 and DIA of 95-108, she's not paralyzed but she's lost all her Energy and strength and it hurts to see, please help.", "answers": "I had a patient who was on bed and paralysed for 1 year. Her daughter’s mobile recordings are there on my youtube channel.\nFood cannot be a solution. Your doctors must have told you about the foods that can help. Your doctors must have given some tonics also. I have had cases where people were energyless due to drinking fluids while recovering from Dengue or other fever. Excess fluids is the cause. Those videos are also on my youtube channel.\nFluid management is the key. Hydration dehydration cycles and walk and rest routines can change the condition in 2 days. More details about these on my profile."}
{"_id": "7997d355", "question": "How long should Mirtazapine be taken if it was prescribed as an appetite stimulant for someone recovering from a stroke, suffering from early onset dementia, and while they were living in a rehabilitation facility?", "answers": "There is no time limit on how long you can take mirtazapine. In addition to increasing appetite, it also great for sleep when taken at night. This is good since people with dementia might have sleep problems."}
{"_id": "5f782578", "question": "My 25 year old sister suffered a massive inter cerebral stroke. When the blood finally was off her brain the doctor said her brain stem had detached. So is it possible for her to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "430f42b0", "question": "In recovering from a stroke, did you feel at any time like part of your brain was stuck in the past; like you had feelings and memories from long ago?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0404d7ba", "question": "Can a person have both kinds of strokes, hemorrhagic and ischemic strokes within 30 days, and can he recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d4b3b3a5", "question": "How has your vision changed since an ocular stroke/Hollenhorst Plaque issue? How much vision did you lose, and how long did it take to recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2c30b568", "question": "My sister is recovering from a stroke. However, she has severe pain on the left shoulder. She also complains about numbness and a tingling sensation on her left hand. What can be the reason?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "923f0395", "question": "My husband had a stroke last year and his right side is paralysed. Even after continuous physiotherapy his right hand is not functioning and has gained pain. It's more than a year now, will his hand recover?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "430a8b89", "question": "What should I do if I am unable to live nor have the courage to die? I am a daughter to a single mother who suffered a stroke recently and is still recovering from it. I have been diagnosed with a debilitating health condition which will worsen life.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "34a0d3c7", "question": "If a person in their late 70s is recovering from a stroke still and has a seizure how badly will the seizure effect them? How?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "f9706f0d", "question": "My mom had a mild cerebral stroke 2 months back, she has recovered a lot and I want to get a follow-up checkup done. Should I be going to a neurologist or an internal medicine specialist would be a better choice?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "bef942bb", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "3601edb2", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "4cc44da5", "question": "How do I explain operant conditioning with the following example? There is a 70 year old patient who had a stroke. He has trouble understanding language and speaking and gives up on recovering, but his wife is supportive and helps him communicate.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "d2c4c37f", "question": "I have been suffering without my vision due to stroke since 2015. also because of that I am suffering severe pains in my body. when will I recover from these things?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0bbdea7b", "question": "Are you able to recover finger movements? If so, what treatment or exercises have you undergone? I’ve been struggling since 2012 post stroke lead to hemorrhage.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9336c5d7", "question": "I have an elderly relative who recently suffered a stroke affecting one of his legs. Although he has recovered to a reasonable extent he is suffering from severe cramps at night and the consultants seem to have no particular route to address this. Any pointers or experience would be most useful?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "2f1f3605", "question": "How do I physically and mentally recover fully from a massive stroke? I am a 22yr old female who is 115lbs. And, I am having a hard time getting my emotions under control (such as, constantly laughing or crying). And, this all happened 7 months ago!", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "a684a89b", "question": "What can you suggest me for speedy recovery from hemiplegia on the left side of my body due to brain stroke? How long shall it take to recover to the best a person can? How long did it take you to reach a stage where you can do tasks?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "1aff2bc4", "question": "What are some positive stroke survivor stories who recovered very early?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "e40b7482", "question": "How can I return to a part-time work? I worked at a management level at a US MNC. Three years ago, I suffered a major heart attack. After that, I suffered three strokes. Thankfully, I recovered fully.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "400fb5be", "question": "I had an aphasia stroke like attack which got recovered on its own in 45.minutes. On consulting a neurologist, he said that Mri scan is normal. Is aphasia common or not-so-serious for a 22 year old?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "494ae186", "question": "Why does my mother's blood sugar go high dramatically after breakfast (200-260) but stays close to normal rest of the day? She is 71 and is recovering from stroke. Has slightly elevated BP.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "9af0e39f", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "39ffe750", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "eda0b060", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "0448d16e", "question": "I met with an accident and had a stroke. Somehow, I survived, but I didn't recover completely. Will I get a normal lifespan? I don't have any bad habit. My age is 21, and I was born in 2000.", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "35679a26", "question": "Can a patient that recovered from a stroke masturbate?", "answers": ""}
{"_id": "16376a8a", "question": "I had a stroke in September 2017 & I haven't recovered. My words are slurred. I don't have any income. What should I do?", "answers": "Where are you? If you're in the US, you should get in touch with Social Security and some sort of Rehabilitation Institution."}
{"_id": "c8dee642", "question": "What are the treatments for someone who is suffering a stroke?", "answers": "The brain has an amazing capability of rewiring itself. I had a stroke 18 years ago. While there was no way to heal the area of the brain that was affected. I was able to relearn and adapt to my new ‘normal’ through intensive physical therapy. Depending on what caused the stroke. Was it a blood clot or a hemorrhage? How old is the stroke patient? If say their left arm is non-functioning the quickest way to help the brain rewire is to restrain the ‘unaffected’ arm. Although, very difficult for the patient it requires the brain to ‘find it’s way’ quicker. Best wishes it does not happen overnight but I know many stroke survivors."}
{"_id": "4eac1979", "question": "What can I do to help a gerbil to recover after having a stroke?", "answers": "Make sure he can reach food and water, is somewhere at least somewhat sheltered, and is going to the bathroom.\nTiny animals, especially ones which are naturally prey for other animals, may find being unable to hide desperately stressful and this stress is not easy for human eyes to see. For that reason, unless your gerbil is already mobile, or showing fairly fast improvement, it may be that euthanasia is the only way to make sure that he or she does not suffer undue distress.\nUnfortunately, other gerbils may have a… not helpful reaction to their debilitated cagemate, so if he currently is not mobile you are likely to need to care for him in a separate cage for now.\nCheck in with your vet, and remember that being a good custodian of tiny lives may include really tough decisions. I’m very sorry. Good luck."}
